<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://pds.jpl.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Service
    xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:service:pds_tools_package</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PDS Tools Package</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Service</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2017-02-09</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>A new version.</description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    <Service>
        <name>PDS Tools Package</name>
        <abstract_desc>The PDS Tools Package is the complete set of supported legacy tools for accessing and reading PDS3 data and labels.</abstract_desc>
        <version_id>4.9</version_id>
        <url>https://pds.nasa.gov/tools/about/pds3-tools/pds-tools-package.shtml</url>
        <release_date>2011-05-09</release_date>
        <service_type>Tool</service_type>
        <interface_type>API</interface_type>
        <interface_type>Command-Line</interface_type>
        <category>Reader</category>
        <category>Validation</category>
        <software_language>C</software_language>
        <software_language>Java</software_language>
        <software_language>Perl</software_language>
        <supported_operating_system_note>The software is available in packages for Solaris, Linux, Windows and Macintosh. For the Macintosh package, only the Label Parser is supported.</supported_operating_system_note>
        <description>
The PDS Tools Package is the complete set of supported legacy tools for accessing and reading PDS3 data and labels. This package contains a single installer file which includes the option to install the following tools: 

Keyword Definition (ddict) - Lists all keywords and their definitions from the specified file(s).
Keyword Verifier (kwvtool) - Lists all keywords and a distinct set of their values from the specified files(s).
Label Parser - The Java-based label parser parses an ODL label and generates an XML representation.
Label Verifier (lvtool) - Performs validation of PDS labels.
Line Analyzer (line) - Analyzes each line of a file and reports anomalies.
Make Index (make_index) - Creates an index file (pdsdd.idx) from a data dictionary file (pdsdd.full).
Perl Validation Toolkit - Validates PDS volumes (includes lvtool and kwvtool).
Table Checker (table_check) - Performs a variety of tests on PDS table objects.
Table to Label Generator (tab2lab) - Generates PDS labels from values in a table.
Table Verifier (tbtool) - Utility for validating, browsing and summarizing data that is organized by rows and columns and is described by a PDS label.

The PDS Tools Package also includes libraries which are utilized by the tools listed above and are available for use in customized applications:

Label Library (lablib) - This library, written in C, can be used to read, process and write PDS labels.
Label Library Light (lablib3) - This library, written in C, can be used to read, process and write PDS labels. Compared to lablib, this library is smaller, faster and has a simpler interface.
ODLC Library (odlc) - This library, written in C, can be used to access data that meet the standards of the PDS.
Object Access Library (oal) - This library, written in C, can be used to access data that meet the standards of the PDS.
        </description>
    </Service>
    <!--
    Submitter Information
    Submitter Name:        Sean Hardman
    Submitter Institution: PDS Engineering Node (JPL)
    Submitter Email:       Sean.Hardman@jpl.nasa.gov
    -->
</Product_Service>
