<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1N00.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1N00.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.v9</logical_identifier>  
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VENERA 9</title>
        <information_model_version>1.23.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2024-12-20</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    Initial creation
                </description>
             </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <!-- <Internal_Reference> -->
        <!--     <lid_reference>the soviets</lid_reference> -->
        <!--     <reference_type>instrument_host_to_agency</reference_type> -->
        <!-- </Internal_Reference> -->
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.venera_9</lid_reference> 
            <reference_type>instrument_host_to_investigation</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:v9.ep</lid_reference>  
            <reference_type>instrument_host_to_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:target:planet.venus</lid_reference>
            <reference_type>instrument_host_to_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
               Johnson, N. L., Handbook of soviet lunar and planetary exploration - volume
               47 science and technology series, Amer. Astronau. Soc. Publ., 1979.
            </reference_text>
            <description>Publication includes discussions of the Venera missions</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
               Varfolomeyev, T., The Soviet Venus programme, Spaceflight, 35, 42-43, Feb. 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>Publication includes discussions of the Venera missions</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
               Harvey, B., The new Russian space programme from competition to collaboration,
               John Wiley and Sons, Chichester, England, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>Publication includes discussions of the Venera missions</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_Host>
        <name>VENERA 9</name> 
        <type>Spacecraft</type>
        <naif_host_id>not applicable</naif_host_id>

        <description>
Venera 9 and 10 were a pair of identical spacecraft prepared for the June 1975
Venus launch opportunity. Venera 9 was the first mission to return pictures
from the surface of Venus, and the first to go into orbit around another
planet. The Venera 9 spacecraft comprised two parts, an orbiter and an
attached descent craft and entry system. The orbiter will be described here.
The orbiter mission was to act as a communications relay for the lander and to
explore cloud layers and atmospheric parameters with instruments including
a French 3500 angstrom UV photometer, a 4000-7000 angstrom photo-polarimeter,
a 1.5 to 3 micron infrared spectrometer, and a 8 - 30 micron infrared
radiometer. The orbiter also carried a camera system, magnetometer, energetic
particle detectors, and charged particle traps.

The orbiter 4V bus was based on the M-71 design, and consisted of a 110 cm
diameter central cylinder comprising the UDMH / nitrogen tetroxide tanks
surrounded by a conical compartment with two solar panel wings and a 1.6 meter
high gain parabolic antenna attached to the curved surface. A bell-shaped unit
holding the KTDU-425A propulsion system was attached to the bottom of the
cylinder, and mounted on top was a 2.4 meter sphere which held the descent
vehicle. Around the base of the cylinder was a pressurized toroid 2.35 meters
in diameter that held electronics and science instruments. Power was supplied
by a pair of solar panel wings extending from opposite sides of the
cylindrical body, each 1.25 x 2.1 meters in size, giving a total span of 6.7
meters. Spacecraft attitude control and knowledge were provided by a gimbaled
engine nozzle, nitrogen cold gas jets, and gyroscopes, with solar sensors,
Canopus star sensors, and an Earth sensor.

Communications were provided via the high gain antenna and six omnidirectional
helical antennas, four for communication with Earth and two for the descent
vehicle. The high gain antenna provided communication with Earth in the
decimeter and centimeter wavelength bands. Command uplink was at 769 MHz
through the helical antennas. A 16 MB magnetic tape system was used for data
storage. A boom holding the magnetometer extended from one of the solar
panels. Thermal control was achieved through use of louvers and a radiator.

At launch the Venera 9 spacecraft, including the descent vehicle, had a mass
of 4936 kg. This included 1093 kg of propellant. The dry mass of the orbiter
was 2283 kg. The nearly identical Venera 10 mission was launched six days
later, on 14 June. 
        </description>
    </Instrument_Host>
</Product_Context>
