<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:issna.co</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Imaging Science Subsystem - Narrow Angle for CO</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2024-10-07</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updates to descriptions and references</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.co</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Porco, C.C., R.A. West, S. Squyres, A. McEwen, P. Thomas, C.D. Murray, A.
                   DelGenio, A.P. Ingersoll, T.V. Johnson, G. Neukum, J. Veverka, L. Dones, A.
                   Brahic, J.A. Burns, V. Haemmerle, B. Knowles, D. Dawson, T. Roatsch, K. Beurle,
                   and W. Owen, Cassini Imaging Science: Instrument Characteristics and
                   Capabilities and Anticipated Scientific Investigations at Saturn, Space Science
                   Reviews 115,363-497, 2004.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.PORCOETAL2004</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Imaging Science Subsystem - Narrow Angle</name>
    <type>Imager</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Camera-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The Imaging Science Subsystem (ISS) on Cassini is intended to study Saturn, Titan, and the other satellites of Saturn. The primary science objectives of the ISS are to: (1) map the three-dimensional structure and motion of the atmospheres of Saturn and Titan; (2) study the composition, distribution, and physical properties of clouds and aerosols; (3) examine scattering, absorpotion, and solar heating within the atmospheres of Saturn/Titan; (4) search for lightning, aurorae, and airglow; (5) investigate the gravitational interactions among Saturn's rings and satellites; (6) determine the nature and rate of energy and momentum transfer within the rings; (7) determine the thickness of the rings as well as the size, composition, and physical nature of the ring particles; (8) map the surfaces of the satellites and determine the composition of their surface materials; and, (9) measure the rotation states of the satellites.
To accomplish these goals, the ISS consists of a wide angle camera and a narrow angle camera. The wide angle camera (WAC) telescope is a 20 cm (f/3.5) refractor while the narrow angle camera (NAC) telescope is a 2 m (f/10.5) refractor. The WAC is planned to cover a wavelength range from 380-1100 nm with 18 separate filters while the NAC covers a range of 200-1100 nm with 24 filters. The WAC's field-of-view is 3.5 degrees with an angular resolution of 60 microradians/pixel. The NAC's field-of-view is 0.35 degrees with an angular resolution of 6.0 microradians/pixel. The imaging plane of each will contain a 1024 x 1024 element CCD array.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
