<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:crism.mro</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Compact Reconnaissance Imaging Spectrometer for Mars (CRISM) for MRO</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2024-10-07</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updates to descriptions and references</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Bugby, D., J. Garzon, M. Beres, C. Stouffer, D. Mehoke, and M. Wirzburger,
                   Cryogenic diode heat pipe system for cryocooler redundancy, in Proc. SPIE,
                   edited by J.B. Heaney and L.G. Burriesci, Vol. 5904, pp. 321-329, 2005.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.BUGBYETAL2005</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Lees, J., E. Schaefer, and M. Fasold, Design of the CRISM cryogenic system and
                   focal plane assembly isolation system, in Proc. SPIE, edited by A.E. Hatheway,
                   Vol. 5877, pp. 265-275, 2005.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.LEESETAL2005</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Murchie, S., R. Arvidson, P. Bedini1, K. Beisser, J.-P. Bibring, J. Bishop, J.
                   Boldt, T. Choo, R.T. Clancy, E.H. Darlington, D. Des Marais, R. Espiritu, M.
                   Fasold, D. Fort, R. Green, E. Guinness, J. Hayes, C. Hash, K. Heffernan, J.
                   Hemmler, G. Heyler, D. Humm, J. Hutchison, N. Izenberg, R. Lee, J. Lees, D.
                   Lohr, E. Malaret, T. Martin, R. Morris, J. Mustard, E. Rhodes, M. Robinson, T.
                   Roush, E. Schaefer, G. Seagrave, P. Silverglate, S. Slavney, M. Smith, K.
                   Strohbehn, H. Taylor, P. Thompson, and B. Tossman, CRISM (Compact
                   Reconnaissance Imaging Spectrometer for Mars) on MRO (Mars Reconnaissance
                   Orbiter), Proc. SPIE, edited by C.A. Nardell, P.G. Lucey, J. Yee, and J.B.
                   Garvin, Vol. 5660, pp. 66-77, 2004.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.MURCHIEETAL2004</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Murchie, S., R.E. Arvidson, P. Bedini, K. Beisser, J.-P. Bibring, J. Bishop, J.
                   Boldt, P. Cavender, T. Choo, R.T. Clancy, E.H. Darlington, D. Des Marais, R.
                   Espiritu, M. Fasold, D. Fort, R. Green, E. Guinness, J. Hayes, C. Hash, K.
                   Heffernan, J. Hemmler, G. Heyler, D. Humm, J. Hutcheson, N. Izenberg, R. Lee,
                   J. Lees, D. Lohr, E. Malaret, T. Martin, J.A. McGovern, R.V. Morris, J.
                   Mustard, S. Pelkey, E. Rhodes, M. Robinson, T. Roush, E. Schaefer, G. Seagrave,
                   F. Seelos, P. Silverglate, S. Slavney, M. Smith, K. Strohbehn, H. Taylor, P.
                   Thompson, B. Tossman , and M. Wolff, CRISM (Compact Reconnaissance Imaging
                   Spectrometer for Mars) on MRO (Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter), J. Geophys. Res.,
                   submitted, 2006.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.MURCHIEETAL2006</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Pelkey, S.M., J.F. Mustard, J.-P. Bibring, R.E. Milliken, Y. Langevin, B.
                   Gondet, A. Gendrin, F. Poulet, S. Erard, S. Murchie, R.E. Arvidson, and the
                   OMEGA and CRISM Science Teams, Global Spectral and Compositional Diversity of
                   Mars: A Test of CRISM Global Mapping with Mars Express OMEGA Data, Lunar and
                   Planetary Science XXXVI, Vol. 1458, 2005.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.PELKEYETAL2005</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Silverglate, P.R., and D.E. Fort, System design of the CRISM (compact
                   reconnaissance imaging spectrometer for Mars) hyperspectral imager, in Proc.
                   SPIE, edited by S.S. Shen and P.E. Lewis, Vol. 5159, pp. 283-290, 2004.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.SILVERGLATE-FORT2004</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Troll, J., P. Thompson, and D. Humm, Boresight and gimbal axis alignment for
                   the CRISM instrument, in Proc. SPIE, edited by A.E. Hatheway, Vol. 5877, pp.
                   93-101, 2005.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.TROLLETAL2005</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Compact Reconnaissance Imaging Spectrometer for Mars</name>
    <type>Imager</type>
    <type>Spectrometer</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Imaging Spectrometer-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>CRISM (Compact Reconnaissance Imaging Spectrometer for Mars) is a hyperspectral imager on the MRO (Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter) spacecraft.  MRO's objectives are to recover climate science originally to have been conducted on the Mars Climate Orbiter (MCO), to identify and characterize sites of possible aqueous activity to which future landed missions may be sent, and to characterize the composition, geology, and stratigraphy of Martian surface deposits. MRO will operate from a sun-synchronous, near- circular (255x320 km altitude), near-polar orbit with a mean local solar time of 3 PM. CRISM's spectral range spans the ultraviolet (UV) to the mid-wave infrared (MWIR), 362 nm to 3920 nm. The instrument utilizes a Ritchey-Chretien telescope with a 2.12 degree field-of-view (FOV) to focus light on the entrance slit of a dual spectrometer. Within the spectrometer, light is split by a dichroic into VNIR (visible-near-infrared, 362-1053 nm) and IR (infrared, 1002-3920 nm) beams. Each beam is directed into a separate modified Offner spectrometer that focuses a spectrally dispersed image of the slit onto a two dimensional focal plane (FP). The IR FP is a 640 x 480 HgCdTe area array; the VNIR FP is a 640 x 480 silicon photodiode area array. The spectral image is contiguously sampled with a 6.55 nm spectral spacing and an instantaneous field of view of 61.5 microradians. The Optical
Sensor Unit (OSU) can be gimbaled to take out along-track smear, allowing long integration times that afford high signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) at high spectral and spatial resolution. The scan motor and encoder are controlled by a separately housed Gimbal Motor Electronics (GME) unit. A Data Processing Unit (DPU) provides power, command and
control, and data editing and compression.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
