<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:ase.phx</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Atmospheric Structure Experiment for PHX</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2018-05-23</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>Changed logical_identifier from ase__phx to ase.phx</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2024-10-07</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updates to descriptions and references</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2024-10-09</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Adding missing "agency" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:agency:agency.nasa</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_agency</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.phx</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.phoenix</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Garavelli, B, L. Marradi, and A. Morgan, Space Qualified GPS Receiver and MIMU
                   for an autonomous on-board guidance and navigation package, Proc. SPIE, 2583,
                   539-547, 1995.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.GARAVELLIETAL1995</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Taylor, P.A., Catling, D.C., Daly, M., Dickinson, C.S., Gunnlaugsson, H.P.,
                   Harri, A.-M., Lange, C.F., Temperature, pressure, and wind instrumentation in
                   the Phoenix meteorological package. Journal of Geophysical Research, 113,
                   E00A10, 2008, doi:10.1029/2007JE003015.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.TAYLORETAL2008</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Atmospheric Structure Experiment</name>
    <type>Atmospheric Sciences</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Inertial Measurement Unit-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The PHX entry capsule contained two Inertial Measurement Units (IMUs) mounted on the underside of the lander on opposite sides of the spacecraft. Only one IMU was used during descent, entry and landing (EDL). The other IMU was a backup device that was not turned on. The Phoenix IMU is quasi-standard commercial product, sometimes called a Miniature IMU, or MIMU [GARAVELLIETAL1995]. This particular device was manufactured by Honeywell (Clearwater, FL) with model number YG9666BC. The IMU used three Allied Signal QFLEX accelerometers for linear acceleration measurement and three Honeywell GG1320 RLG ring-laser gyros for angular rotation measurement. However, the IMU was configured internally so that the linear accelerations were integrated and output as linear velocity changes while the gyro measurements were output as angle changes in a given sample time. No input from scientists was possible concerning the device selection and location within the lander, which was done by spacecraft engineers for the cancelled NASA Mars 2001 Lander prior to the initiation of the Phoenix project. The Phoenix lander was based on the Mars 2001 Lander design. Consequently, the IMU used during EDL of the Phoenix spacecraft was neither located at the entry vehicle center of mass nor the spin axis, which otherwise would have been desirable to optimize noise minimization for scientific purposes. At a rate of 200 Hz, the IMU output the accumulated linear velocity change (the time integral of acceleration) in three Cartesian axes and accumulated angle change (the time integral of angular rate) about three Cartesian axes. Data was saved onboard PHX at the device output rate of 200 Hz and was not down-sampled. The IMU had a mass of 3.52 kg and approximately 4051 cc volume.  Each accelerometer within the IMU had a full-scale range of 36.8g (where g represents Earth's standard surface gravitational acceleration of 9.80665 meters per second per second). The accelerometer and gyro signals were electronically integrated inside the IMU to produce an output of accumulated delta-v (linear velocity change) and delta-q (angular velocity change) at 200 Hz.  The accelerometers had two stages of digitization that resulted in pulses and then counts. The final raw digital output from the IMU accelerometers was in counts, in velocity units, where 1 output count = 0.0753 mm/sec.  But the final output moved up and down in pulses, which are leaps of many counts, with each pulse equivalent to 2.7 mm/sec. Thus, the amplitude of one pulse was equivalent to 2.7/0.0753 = 35.86 counts, on average. Added to this was noise in the system, which was on the order of 1 count, so that jumps in the raw output were typically 36 or 37 counts. This determined the digital resolution of the raw 200 Hz data to be a delta-v of 2.7 mm/sec and typical noise level of 0.0753 mm/sec. Individual gyros measure the angular rotation about one axis. Each raw IMU gyro output is a 16 bit signed integer (i.e., from -32767 to +32767) with the least significant bit (LSB) equivalent to 1 micro-radian. Because the data was generated at 200 Hz or every 5 millisecs, a full-scale value of 32768 would correspond to 375 deg/sec. (32,768 * 1 microradian /0.005 sec = 0.032768/0.005 radian/sec = 6.5536 rad/sec = 375 deg/sec). The smallest motion in a 200 Hz interval is one count, which corresponds to 0.01144 deg/sec (1 * 1 microradian /0.005 sec = 200 micro-rad/sec = 0.01144 deg/sec). Smaller angular motions can be measured over longer time periods by integration of the raw data. Noise on the raw gyro output is estimated as 45 micro-radians (3 sigma).</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
