<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:rss.vo2</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>RADIO SCIENCE SUBSYSTEM for VO2</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2024-10-22</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. LIDVID references updated to be LID references. Adding missing "investigation" references. Adding missing "agency" references. Description updated.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:agency:agency.nasa</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_agency</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.pre-magellan</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.viking</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.vo2</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Sjogren, W.L., Mars Gravity: High-resolution results from Viking Orbiter 2,
                   Science, 203, 1006-1010, 1979.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.SJOGREN1979</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>RADIO SCIENCE SUBSYSTEM</name>
    <type>Atmospheric Sciences</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Radio Science-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>There are four distinct sets of Viking radio science data, three using orbiter data and one primarily using lander data with calibrations from orbiter data. The orbiter tracking data, obtained from the two-way, orbiter-earth S-band and X-band radio links, consist of Doppler frequencies and time-of-flight range measurements. These determined the position and motion of the orbiters, and can be used to study the Mars gravitational field, the plasma in interplanetary space, and the structure of the solar corona when the spacecraft was on the opposite side of the sun. The occultation data were obtained from these same radio links by analog recording of the signal when a spacecraft was passing into or out of occultation with Mars. The data can be used to produce altitude profiles of the temperature, density, and pressure of the atmosphere (including the ionosphere) and to measure the radius of the planet using a large number of surface points. The surface properties aspect of this investigation utilized the UHF (381 MHz) signal on which the landers transmitted data to the orbiters. At the beginning or end of a data transmission session, when the orbiter was near the lander's horizon, the strength of the received signal was recorded as a function of time. These signal "fading patterns," resulting from interaction of the radio waves with the Martian surface, contain information about the physical properties of the surface near the landers. The lander tracking data from the two-way direct lander-earth S-band links permit determination of the location of the landers and studies of the motion of the planet.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
