<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Mission_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Mission_PDS3</product_class>
        <Alias_List>
            <Alias>
                <alternate_id>MESS</alternate_id>
                <alternate_title>MESS</alternate_title>
            </Alias>
        </Alias_List>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Solomon, S.C., R.L. McNutt, Jr., R.E. Gold, and D.L. Domingue, MESSENGER
                   mission overview, Space Science Reviews, 131, 3-39, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SOLOMONETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>

    <Mission_PDS3>
        <mission_name>MESSENGER</mission_name>
        <mission_desc>
 
   MESSENGER Mission Overview
   ==========================
     The MErcury Surface, Space ENvironment, GEochemistry,
     and Ranging (MESSENGER) spacecraft was launched from
     the Cape Canaveral Air Station on 2004-08-03, on an
     approximately 8 year mission to become the first
     probe to orbit the planet Mercury.
 
     The MESSENGER payload consists of seven instruments
     and a radio science (RS) experiment.  The instruments
     are the Mercury Dual Imaging System (MDIS), the Gamma-
     Ray and Neutron Spectrometer (GRNS), the X-Ray
     Spectrometer (XRS), the Magnetometer (MAG), the
     Mercury Laser Altimeter (MLA), the Mercury Atmospheric
     and Surface Composition Spectrometer (MASCS), and the
     Energetic Particle and Plasma Spectrometer (EPPS).
 
     The MESSENGER mission is fully described in
     [SOLOMONETAL2007].
 
     MDIS
     ----
       The MDIS instrument includes both a wide-angle (WA)
       and a narrow-angle (NA) camera and both are capable
       of summing pixels.  This provides for images of the
       surface that are of nearly uniform horizontal
       resolution (125 m per pixel or better throughout
       MESSENGER&apos;s elliptical orbit).  The WA and NA
       cameras (WAC and NAC) are mounted on opposite sides
       of a pivot platform, making MDIS the only MESSENGER
       instrument capable of pointing independent of
       spacecraft attitude.
 
       MDIS contributes to the understanding of the
       geological landforms and processes that shaped
       Mercury&apos;s surface.
 
     GRNS
     ----
       The GRNS instrument includes two sensors, a Gamma-
       Ray Spectrometer (GRS) and a Neutron Spectrometer
       (NS).  The GRS is a germanium detector with an
       active shield capable of measuring the elemental
       abundances of O, Si, S, Fe, H, K, Th, and U.  The NS
       sensor consists of two lithium glass scintillators
       separated by a thick slab of borated plastic
       scintillator.  The glass scintillators measure
       thermal neutrons, while the borated-plastic
       scintillator counts fast neutrons.
 
       GRNS contributes to the understanding of surface
       elemental abundances and the composition of polar
       deposits.
 
     XRS
     ---
       The XRS detects solar-induced X-ray fluorescence to
       measure the surface abundances of Mg, Al, Si, Ca, Ti
       and Fe.  Three proportional counters measure low-
       energy X-rays from the planet, while a Si-PIN
       detector located on the spacecraft sunshade measures
       the solar X-ray input.  The XRS has a field of view (FOV)
       of 12 degrees and covers an energy range from 1 to 10 keV.
 
       XRS contributes to the understanding of surface
       elemental abundances.
 
     MAG
     ---
       The MAG instrument is a miniaturized three-axis,
       ring-core, fluxgate magnetometer mounted on a
       lightweight 3.6 m carbon-fiber boom extending from
       the spacecraft in the anti-sunward direction.  It
       samples the field at a 20-Hz rate with selectable
       readout intervals between 0.04 s to 1 s. Readout
       intervals of greater than 1 s generate a 0.5 s
       average.
 
       MAG contributes to the mapping of Mercury&apos;s internal
       magnetic field and to understanding the
       magnetospheric structure.
 
     MLA
     ---
       The MLA consists of a 1064 nm laser transmitter and
       four sapphire lens receiver telescopes.  It is
       capable of measuring altitudes to a 30-cm precision
       at ranges up to 1000 km.  Because of this range, the
       MLA will operate for about 30 minutes around the
       periapsis of each orbit.
 
       MLA contributes to the mapping of the northern
       hemisphere topography and the altimetry of polar
       craters and is instrumental in determining Mercury&apos;s
       gravity field, obliquity and libration amplitude.
 
     MASCS
     -----
       The MASCS instrument combines a movable-grating
       Ultraviolet-Visible Spectrometer (UVVS) and a
       Visible-Infrared Spectrograph (VIRS) into one
       package. Both instruments share a single front-end
       telescope.  UVVS spans the spectral range from 115
       to 600 nm with an average spectral resolution of 1
       nm, has a 25 km altitude resolution, and is
       optimized for measuring very weak exospheric
       emissions.  VIRS measures the visible (300-1025 nm)
       and infrared (0.95-1.45 um) spectral ranges
       utilizing a 512 element detector for the visible and
       a 256 element detector for the infrared.
 
       MASCS contributes to the understanding of the
       composition of Mercury&apos;s surface in association with
       particular geological units, and to the
       understanding of neutral species in the exosphere
       especially near the polar regions.
 
     EPPS
     ----
       EPPS consists of an Energetic Particle Spectrometer
       (EPS)and a Fast Imaging Plasma Spectrometer (FIPS).
       The EPS measures the time-of-flight and residual
       energy of ions from 10 keV/nucleon to ~3 MeV and
       electrons to 400 keV.  Its FOV, 160 degrees by 12
       degrees, is divided into six segments of 25 degrees
       each.  The FIPS measures thermal and low-energy ions
       and is sensitive over nearly a full hemisphere, with
       energy per charge (E/q) up to &gt; 15 keV/q.
 
       EPPS contributes to the understanding of the solar
       environment associated with Mercury and its
       magnetosphere.
 
     RS
     --
       The spacecraft&apos;s radio frequency (RF)
       telecommunications system is for communications,
       navigation and radio science (RS).  Precise
       observation of the spacecraft&apos;s Doppler velocity and
       range are used to assist in navigating the
       spacecraft. These observations will be inverted to
       determine the effect of the planet&apos;s gravitational
       field on the spacecraft.  Occultation observations
       of the spacecraft&apos;s RF signal will provide necessary
       measurements of Mercury&apos;s shape in the southern
       hemisphere.
 
       RS contributes to the understanding of Mercury&apos;s
       gravity field, obliquity and libration amplitude
       (Doppler observations) and its global topography,
       especially the southern hemisphere (occultation
       observations).
 
   Mission Phases
   ==============
     Nineteen mission phases were defined for significant
     spacecraft activity periods.  The large number of
     phases is due to the complex sequence of gravitational
     assists necessary to bring the spacecraft into orbit
     around Mercury while maintaining a minimal mass due to
     fuel.  This consideration lead to one Earth flyby, two
     Venus flybys, and three Mercury flybys before orbit
     insertion at Mercury.
 
     The mission phases are defined naturally by the
     various planetary encounters and their intervening
     cruise periods. Given the short encounter times for
     each MESSENGER flyby, we define encounter phases on
     the basis of a 4 week period centered on the closest
     approach to each target body (two weeks before and two
     after) and separate such encounter segments by cruise
     phases. The cruise periods and flybys are named
     according to the planetary body involved. Also defined
     are a launch and an orbit phase.
 
     The mission phases are: Launch, Earth Cruise, Earth
     Flyby, Venus 1 Cruise, Venus 1 Flyby, Venus 2 Cruise,
     Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise, Mercury 1 Flyby,
     Mercury 2 Cruise, Mercury 2 Flyby, Mercury 3 Cruise,
     Mercury 3 Flyby, Mercury 4 Cruise, Mercury Orbit,
     Mercury Orbit Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3,
     Mercury Orbit Year 4, and Mercury Orbit Year 5.
 
     Launch
     ------
       The launch phase has been defined to capture
       instrument data produced between launch and the
       beginning of Phase E.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2004-08-03 (2004-216)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2004-09-12 (2004-256)
 
     Earth Cruise
     ------------
       Earth Cruise is the period of time between launch
       and the week before closest approach to Earth.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2004-09-13 (2004-257)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2005-07-18 (2005-199)
 
     Earth Flyby
     -----------
       Earth Flyby is defined as the four week (28 day)
       period centered on closest approach to Earth.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2005-07-19 (2005-200)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2005-08-16 (2005-228)
 
     Venus 1 Cruise
     --------------
       Venus 1 Cruise is defined as the period between the
       Earth flyby and the first Venus flyby.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2005-08-17 (2005-229)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2006-10-09 (2006-282)
 
     Venus 1 Flyby
     -------------
       Venus 1 Flyby is defined as the four week (28 day)
       period centered on the first of the mission&apos;s two
       closest approaches to Venus.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2006-10-10 (2006-283)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2006-11-07 (2006-311)
 
     Venus 2 Cruise
     --------------
       Venus 2 Cruise is defined as the period between the
       first and second Venus flyby.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2006-11-08 (2006-312)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2007-05-22 (2007-142)
 
     Venus 2 Flyby
     -------------
       Venus 2 Flyby is defined as the four week (28 day)
       period centered on the second of the mission&apos;s two
       closest approaches to Venus.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2007-05-23 (2007-143)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2007-06-20 (2007-171)
 
     Mercury 1 Cruise
     ----------------
       Mercury 1 Cruise is defined as the period between
       the second Venus flyby and first Mercury flyby.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2007-06-21 (2007-172)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2007-12-30 (2007-364)
 
     Mercury 1 Flyby
     ---------------
       Mercury 1 Flyby is defined as the four week (28 day)
       period centered on the first of the mission&apos;s three
       closest approaches to Mercury.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2007-12-31 (2007-365)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2008-01-28 (2008-028)
 
     Mercury 2 Cruise
     ----------------
       Mercury 2 Cruise is defined as the period between
       the first and second Mercury flyby.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2008-01-29 (2008-029)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2008-09-21 (2008-265)
 
     Mercury 2 Flyby
     ---------------
       Mercury 2 Flyby is defined as the four week (28 day)
       period centered on the second of the mission&apos;s three
       closest approaches to Mercury.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2008-09-22 (2008-266)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2008-10-20 (2008-294)
 
     Mercury 3 Cruise
     ----------------
       Mercury 3 Cruise is defined as the period between
       the second and third Mercury flyby.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2008-10-21 (2008-295)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2009-09-15 (2009-258)
 
     Mercury 3 Flyby
     ---------------
       Mercury 3 Flyby is defined as the four week (28 day)
       period centered on the third of the mission&apos;s three
       closest approaches to Mercury.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2009-09-16 (2009-259)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2009-10-14 (2009-287)
 
     Mercury 4 Cruise
     ----------------
       Mercury 4 Cruise is defined as the period between
       the third Mercury flyby and Mercury orbit insertion.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2009-10-15 (2009-288)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2011-03-03 (2011-062)
 
     Mercury Orbit
     -------------
       The Orbit phase begins at Mercury orbit insertion
       and continues until the end of mission. This phase
       begins the most intensive science portion of the mission
       with full instrument utilization throughout the
       period.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2011-03-04 (2011-063)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2012-03-17 (2012-077)
 
     Mercury Orbit Year 2
     --------------------
       The Orbit phase year 2 begins the extended mission. This phase
       continues the most intensive science portion of the mission
       with full instrument utilization throughout the period.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2012-03-18 (2012-078)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2013-03-17 (2013-076)
 
     Mercury Orbit Year 3
     --------------------
       The Orbit phase year 3 continues the extended mission. This phase
       continues the most intensive science portion of the mission
       with full instrument utilization throughout the period.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2013-03-18 (2013-077)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2014-03-17 (2014-076)
 
     Mercury Orbit Year 4
     --------------------
       The Orbit phase year 4 continues the extended mission. This phase
       continues the most intensive science portion of the mission with
       full instrument utilization throughout the period.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2014-03-18 (2014-077)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2015-03-17 (2015-076)
 
     Mercury Orbit Year 5
     --------------------
       The Orbit phase year 5 continues the extended mission through to
       the end of orbital operations. This phase continues the most
       intensive science portion of the mission with full instrument
       utilization through near the end of the period which ended when
       the spacecraft impacted Mercury as expected on 30 April 2015.
 
       Mission Phase Start Time : 2015-03-18 (2014-077)
       Mission Phase Stop Time  : 2015-04-30 (2015-120)
        </mission_desc>
        <mission_objectives_summary>
 
   Primary Mission
   ---------------
   The primary MESSENGER mission has six guiding science
   questions, which in turn correlate to specific science
   objects and a set of measurement requirements related
   to specific instruments. These guiding questions are:
 
   (1) What planetary formational processes led to
   the high metal/silicate ratio in Mercury?
   (2) What is the geological history of Mercury?
   (3) What are the nature and origin of Mercury&apos;s
   magnetic field?
   (4) What are the structure and state of Mercury&apos;s
   core?
   (5) What are the radar-reflective materials at
   Mercury&apos;s poles?
   (6) What are the important volatile species and
   their sources and sinks on and near Mercury?
 
   The related science objectives and instrument
   measurement requirements are:
 
   (1) Map the elemental and mineralogical composition
   of Mercury&apos;s surface.
   GRNS and XRS: Provide major-element maps of
   Mercury to 10% relative uncertainty on the 1000-
   km scale. Elements to be measured include: O, Si,
   S, Fe, H, K, U (by GRS); thermal and epithermal
   neutrons (by NS), and Fe, Mg, Ca, Al, Si, Ti, S
   (by XRS).
   MASCS (VIRS): Determine local composition and
   mineralogy at the ~20-km scale.
 
   (2) Image globally the surface at a resolution of
   hundreds of meters or better.
   MDIS (WAC): Provide a global multi-spectral map
   at 2 km/pixel average resolution.
   MDIS (NAC): Provide a global map with &gt; 90%
   coverage (monochrome) at 250-m average
   resolution.
   MDIS: Image &gt; 80% of the planet stereoscopically.
   Provide color images with a resolution to 1
   km/pixel.
   MLA: Sample half of the northern hemisphere for
   topography at 1.5-m average height resolution
 
   (3) Determine the structure of the planet&apos;s magnetic
   field.
   MAG: Provide a multipole magnetic-field model
   resolved through quadrupole terms with an
   uncertainty of less than ~20% in the dipole
   magnitude and direction.
 
   (4) Measure the libration amplitude and
   gravitational field structure.
   MLA &amp; RS: Provide a global gravity field to
   degree and order 16 and determine the ratio of
   the solid-planet moment of inertia to the total
   moment of inertia to ~20% or better.
 
   (5) Determine the composition of the radar-
   reflective materials at Mercury&apos;s poles.
   GRNS: Identify the principal component of the
   radar-reflective material at Mercury&apos;s north
   pole.
 
   (6) Characterize exosphere neutrals and accelerated
   magnetosphere ions.
   MASCS (UVVS): Provide altitude profiles at 25-km
   resolution of the major neutral exospheric
   species.
   EPPS: Characterize the major ion-species energy
   distributions as functions of local time, Mercury
   Heliocentric distance, and solar activity.
 
   First Extended Mission
   ----------------
   The first extended MESSENGER mission has six additional
   guiding science questions, which in turn correlate to specific
   science objects and a set of measurement requirements related
   to specific instruments. These guiding questions are:
 
       (1) What are the sources of surface volatiles?
       (2) How late into Mercury&apos;s history did volcanism persist?
       (3) How did Mercury&apos;s long-wavelength topography change with
           time?
       (4) What is the origin of localized regions of enhanced
           exospheric density near Mercury?
       (5) How does the solar cycle affect Mercury&apos;s exosphere and
           volatile transport?
       (6) What is the origin of Mercury&apos;s energetic electrons?
 
   The related science objectives and instrument measurement requirements
   are:
 
   (1) Determine the morphological and compositional context of
   &apos;hollows&apos; and their relationship to bright crater-floor deposits and
   pyroclastic vents
 
   MDIS (WAC): Image 70% of the planet in three colors at 600 m/pixel
   average spatial resolution. MDIS (NAC): Acquire 100 sets of targeted
   images of hollows or pyroclastic vents at 60 m/pixel average spatial
   resolution. MASCS (VIRS): Acquire 20 targeted VIRS observations of
   hollows and pyroclastic vents at low solar incidence angle (i).
 
   (2) Acquire targeted, high-resolution observations of volcanic
   materials of low impact crater density identified in the primary
   mission
 
   MDIS (NAC): Acquire 30 sets of targeted images of young volcanic
   materials at 60 m/pixel average spatial resolution.
 
   (3) Document changes in long-wavelength topography versus geological
   time on Mercury from altimetric and complementary imaging
   measurements MDIS: Image 70% of the planet at 250 m/pixel average
   spatial resolution, targeting i ~ 40 deg. to 65 deg., MDIS: Image 70%
   of the planet at 250 m/pixel average spatial resolution, targeting i
   ~ 75 deg. to 85 deg., and MLA: Provide topographic profiles over 10
   broadly elevated regions and the floors of 50 complex impact craters,
   including volcanically flooded craters.
 
   (4) Characterize regions of enhanced density versus solar distance,
   proximity to geologic units, solar activity, and magnetospheric
   conditions MASCS (UVVS): Survey dayside and nightside exosphere
   emissions at an average rate of once every third orbit, MASCS (UVVS):
   During dawn-dusk seasons, conduct repeated observations of exospheric
   emission over both poles to the maximum extent permitted by
   spacecraft pointing constraints, and MASCS (UVVS): Conduct
   full-orbit, exosphere observation campaigns at equally spaced Mercury
   true anomalies over each of four Mercury years.
 
   (5) Measure changes in exospheric neutrals and plasma ions as solar
   activity increases EPPS (FIPS): Measure the global distribution of
   planetary ions and the direction of plasma flow, within operational
   constraints.
 
   (6) Infer the sources and energization mechanism from the location,
   energy spectra, and temporal profiles of energetic electrons
 
   EPPS (EPS) &amp; MAG: Provide locations, energy spectra and pitch angles,
   and temporal profiles of energetic electrons across all magnetic
   longitudes in the northern hemisphere.
 
   Second Extended Mission
   ----------------
   The second extended MESSENGER mission has seven additional
   guiding science questions, which in turn correlate to specific
   science objects and a set of measurement requirements related
   to specific instruments. These guiding questions are:
 
       (1) What active and recent processes have affected
           Mercury&apos;s surface?
       (2) How has the state of stress in Mercury&apos;s crust
           evolved over time?
       (3) How have the compositions of volcanic materials on
           Mercury evolved over time?
       (4) What are the characteristics of volatile emplacement
           and sequestration in Mercury&apos;s north polar region?
       (5) What are the consequences of precipitating ions and
           electrons at Mercury?
       (6) How do Mercury&apos;s exosphere and magnetosphere respond
           to both extreme and stable solar wind conditions during
           solar wind conditions during solar maximum and the
           declining phase of the solar cycle?
       (7) What novel insights into Mercury&apos;s thermal and crustal
           evolution can be obtained with high-resolution measurements
           from low altitudes?
 
   The related science objectives and instrument measurement
   requirements are:
 
   (1) Characterize faulted terrain by acquiring at least one
   of the following: (a) 20 NAC along-track stereo pairs or
   (b) 40 MLA topographic profiles.
 
   (2) Characterize fresh craters by acquiring at least one
   of the following: (a) 20 WAC 11-color image sets or
   (b) 20 NAC along-track stereo pairs.
 
   (3) Characterize hollows by acquiring (a) UVVS observations
   of exospheric species over eight clusters of hollows on three
   different dates and from two different viewing geometries per
   feature or (b) 20 along-track NAC stereo pairs and 20 11-color
   image sets each.
 
   (4) Characterize surface features at very high resolution by
   acquiring 750 NAC images at &lt;= 10-m pixel scale and 100 NAC images
   at &lt;= 5-m pixel scale.
 
   (5) Search for color variations within the northern plains by
   acquiring 5-color MDIS images of 75% of the surface area north
   of 60 deg N at phase angles &lt; 60 deg.
 
   (6) Constrain the elemental composition of spectral end-member
   materials by acquiring targeted XRS spectra from
   (a) the large pyroclastic deposit northeast of Rachmaninoff and
   (b) of at least two different portions of low-reflectance blue
   plains exterior to the Caloris basin. For each target, acquire a
   minimum of 1000 s of spectral integration spread over at least
   five different orbits.
 
   (7) (a) Characterize MLA-bright and dark materials by acquiring
   MLA ranging and reflectance data along portions of two orbits for
   which ground tracks cross each of 10 craters &lt; 20 km in diameter, and
   (b) characterize the north polar hydrogen distribution at high spatial
   resolution by acquiring NS measurements for 70% of the time that the
   spacecraft altitude is less than 150 km.
 
   (8) Characterize crustal structure at high resolution by acquiring
   Doppler tracking data for portions of 100 orbits at altitudes &lt; 100 km.
 
   (9) Characterize the structure of crustal magnetization at high
   resolution by acquiring MAG and FIPS observations along portions of
   100 orbits at altitudes &lt; 50 km in the vicinity of the northern plains.
 
   (10) Characterize magnetospheric particle flows and pitch-angle
   distributions by acquiring a defined set of 970 EPPS measurements
   distributed across several different pointing scenarios.
 
   (11) Characterize the exospheric response to conditions during
   solar maximum and the declining phase of the solar cycle by acquiring
   a defined set of 5025 UVVS dayside and nightside observations,
   including searches for species with weaker resonant emissions.
 
   (12) Characterize the magnetospheric response to conditions during
   solar maximum and the declining phase of the solar cycle by acquiring
   MAG, EPPS and NS/GRS observations for 75% of the time throughout the
   mission, including times at which the spacecraft altitude is &lt; 50 km.
        </mission_objectives_summary>
        <mission_start_date>2004-08-03</mission_start_date>
        <mission_stop_date>2015-04-30</mission_stop_date>
    </Mission_PDS3>
</Product_Mission_PDS3>
