<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:m3.ch1-orb</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>MOON MINERALOGY MAPPER for CH1-ORB</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. LIDVID references updated to be LID references. Adding missing "investigation" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.chandrayaan-1</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.ch1-orb</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Green, R.O., C. Pieters, P. Mouroulis, and T. Koch, Moon Mineralogy Mapper
                   Imaging Spectrometer Science Measurements, 2008 IEEE Aerospace Conference,
                   Paper #1438, Ver. 4, 2008, doi:10.1109/AERO.2008.4526382.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.GREENETAL2008A</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Green, R.O., C.M. Pieters, P. Mouroulis, G. Sellar, M. Eastwood, S. Geier, J.
                   Shea, and M3 Team, Calibration, Shipment and Initial Spacecraft Integration of
                   the Moon Mineralogy Mapper (M3) Imaging Spectrometer for the Chandrayaan-1
                   Mission, Lunar and Planetary Institute, 39th Lunar and Planetary Science
                   Conference, LPI Contribution No. 1391, p. 1803, 2008.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.GREENETAL2008B</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Green, R.O., C.M. Pieters, J. Boardman, D. Barr, C. Bruce, J. Bousman, A.
                   Chatterjee, M. Eastwood, V. Essandoh, S. Geier, T. Glavich, R. Green, V.
                   Haemmerle, S. Hyman, L. Hovland, T. Koch, K. Lee, S. Lundeen, S., E. Motts, P.
                   Mouroulis, S. Paulson, K. Plourde, C. Racho, D. Robison, J. Rodriguez, P.
                   Rothman, G. Sellar, C. Smith, H. Sobel, J. Stamp, H. Tseng, P. Varanasi, D,
                   Wilson, and M. White, The Moon Mineralogy Mapper (M3) Imaging Spectrometer:
                   Early Assessment of the Spectral, Radiometric, Spatial, and Uniformity
                   Characteristics, Lunar and Planetary Institute, 40th Lunar and Planetary
                   Science Conference, id. 2307, 2009.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.GREENETAL2009</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Petro, N., C. Pieters, J. Boardman, R. Green, J. Head, P. Isaacson, J. Nettles,
                   E. Malaret, M. Staid, J. Sunshine, and S. Tompkins, Targeting for the Moon
                   Mineralogy Mapper (M3) Instrument on the Chandrayaan-1 Mission, Lunar and
                   Planetary Institute, 39th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, LPI
                   Contribution No. 1391, p. 1696, 2008.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.PETROETAL2008</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Pieters, C.M., J. Boardman, B. Buratti, A. Chatterjee, R. Clark, T. Glavich, R.
                   Green, J. Head, P. Isaacson, E. Malaret, T. McCord, J. Mustard, N. Petro, C.
                   Runyon, M. Staid, J. Sunshine, L. Taylor, S. Tompkins, P. Varanasi, and M.
                   White, The Moon Mineralogy Mapper (M3) on Chandrayaan-1, Indian Academy of
                   Sciences, Current Science, Vol. 96, No. 4, pp. 500-505, 2009.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.PIETERSETAL2009A</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Pieters, C.M., J. Boardman, B. Buratti, R. Clark, J-P. Combe, R. Green, J.N.
                   Goswami, J.W. Head, M. Hicks, P. Isaacson, R. Klima, G. Kramer, S. Kumar, S.
                   Lundeen, E. Malaret, T.B. McCord, J. Mustard, J. Nettles, N. Petro, C. Runyon,
                   M. Staid, J. Sunshine, L. Taylor, S. Tompkins, and P. Varanasi, Mineralogy of
                   the Lunar Crust in Spatial Context: First Results from the Moon Mineralogy
                   Mapper (M3), Lunar and Planetary Institute, 40th Lunar and Planetary Science
                   Conference, id. 2052, 2009.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.PIETERSETAL2009B</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Pieters, C.M., J.N. Goswami, R.N. Clark, M. Annadurai, J. Boardman, B. Buratti,
                   J.-P. Combe, M.D. Dyar, R. Green, J.W. Head, C. Hibbitts, M. Hicks, P.
                   Isaacson, R. Klima, G, Kramer, S. Kumar, E. Livo, S. Lundeen, E. Malaret, T.
                   McCord, J. Mustard, J. Nettles, N. Petro, C. Runyon, M. Staid, J. Sunshine,
                   L.A. Taylor, S. Tompkins, and P. Varanasi, Character and Spatial Distribution
                   of OH/H2O on the Surface of the Moon Seen by M3 on Chandrayaan-1, Science, Vol.
                   326, No. 5952, 568-572, 2009, doi:10.1126/science.1178658.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.PIETERSETAL2009C</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>MOON MINERALOGY MAPPER for CH1-ORB</name>
    <type>Imager</type>
    <type>Spectrometer</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Imaging Spectrometer-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The Moon Mineralogy Mapper (M3 or "M-cubed") is an imaging spectrometer designed to map the mineral content of the Moon's surface. The primary scientific objectives are to characterize and map the lunar surface composition in the context of its geologic evolution and to assess the Moon's mineral resources at high resolution with the goals of studying the origin and evolution of the lunar crust and mantle, identifying and assessing deposits containing volatile species, and identifying and evaluating concentrations of unusual or unexpected minerals.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
