<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:ctli="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:clps_to_2ab_pll.pitms</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>The CLPS Task Order 2-AB Peregrine Lunar Lander Package for Resource Observation and In-Situ Prospecting for Exploration, Commercial Exploration and Transportation Ion-Trap Mass Spectrometer for Lunar Surface Volatiles</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-02-16</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. Adding missing "investigation" references. Title and name of PITMS was corrected</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2024-05-13</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>Initial version.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:other_investigation.clps</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.clps_to_2ab</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.clps_to_2ab_pll</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>The CLPS Task Order 2-AB Peregrine Lunar Lander Package for Resource Observation and In-Situ Prospecting for Exploration, Commercial Exploration and Transportation Ion-Trap Mass Spectrometer for Lunar Surface Volatiles</name>
    <Type_List_Area>
      <ctli:Type_List>
        <ctli:type>Mass Spectrometer</ctli:type>
      </ctli:Type_List>
    </Type_List_Area>
    <description>The CLPS Task Order 2-AB Package for Resource Observation and In-Situ Prospecting for Exploration, Commercial Exploration and Transportation (PROSPECT) Ion-Trap Mass Spectrometer (PITMS) for Lunar Surface Volatiles can characterize the lunar exosphere after descent and landing, and throughout the lunar day, to understand the release and movement of volatile species. Previous missions have demonstrated the presence of volatiles at the lunar surface, but significant questions remain about the where those volatiles came from and how they are transported across the lunar surface. Investigating how the lunar exosphere changes over the course of a lunar day can provide insight into the transport process for volatiles on the Moon. The instrument has the ability to measure the low level of gases expected in the lunar exosphere and released by regolith interaction with surface disturbances, like rovers. The PITMS sensor has direct heritage from the Ptolemy mass spectrometer that made the first in situ measurements of volatiles and organics on comet 67P with the Rosetta lander, Philae. PITMS operates in a passive sampling mode, where molecules fall into the zenith-facing aperture and are trapped by a radiofrequency field, then sequentially released for analysis. PITMS has a unit mass resolution up to an upper mass-to-charge (m/z) limit of 150 Da. The PITMS investigation will provide time-resolved variability of OH, H2O, noble gases, nitrogen, and sodium compounds released from the soil and present in the exosphere over the course of a lunar day. PITMS is a joint NASA-ESA project implemented by NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC) and ESA's contractors Open University (OU) and STFC RAL Space, with coordination and support provided by ESA's Space Research and Technology Centre (ESTEC). The integrated PITMS payload and science investigation will be operated by GSFC with an international team of scientists.         </description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
