<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:cda.co</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Cosmic Dust Analyzer for CO</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. LIDVID references updated to be LID references. Adding missing "investigation" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.co</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Srama, R., T.J. Ahrens, N. Altobelli, S. Auer, J.G. Bradley, M. Burton, V.V.
                   Dikarev, T. Economou, H. Fechtig, M. Goerlich, M. Grande, A. Graps, E. Gruen,
                   O. Havnes, S. Helfert, M. Horanyi, E. Igenbergs, E.K. Jessberger, T.V. Johnson,
                   S. Kempf, A.V. Krivov, H. Krueger, A. Mocker-Ahlreep, G. Moragas-Klostermeyer,
                   P. Lamy, M. Landgraf, D. Linkert, G. Linkert, F. Lura, J.A.M. McDonnell, D.
                   Moehlmann, G.E. Morfill, M. Mueller, M. Roy, G. Schaefer, G. Schlotzhauer, G.H.
                   Schwehm, F. Spahn, M. Stuebig, J. Svestka, V. Tschernjawski, A.J. Tuzzolino, R.
                   Waesch, H.A. Zook, The Cassini Cosmic Dust Analyzer. Space Sci. Rev., Volume
                   114, Issue 1-4, pp.465-518, 2004
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.SRAMAETAL2004B</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Cosmic Dust Analyzer for CO</name>
    <type>Dust</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Cosmic Dust Analyzer -->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The Cosmic Dust Analyser (CDA) aboard the Cassini orbiter represents a significant advancement in cosmic dust detection technology, succeeding the instruments utilized in the Ulysses and Galileo missions. The CDA employs dual methodologies for dust impact detection: a High Rate Detector (HRD) comprising two polyvinylidene fluoride (PVDF) sensors, and a Dust Analyser (DA) based on impact ionization. The DA provides comprehensive measurements, including charge, impact direction, velocity, mass, and elemental composition of dust particles, whereas the HRD is limited to mass determination of particles with predetermined velocities. The DA encompasses a charge detection unit, an impact ionization detector, and a time-of-flight (TOF) mass spectrometer. Notably, the charge detection unit generates high-frequency 'QP signals' primarily for large particles (&gt;5 microns), leading to infrequent triggering during cruise phases and selective transmission of data to Earth. The intricate design of the charge detection unit allows for the resolution of particle speed and direction, while the impact ionization detector utilizes a dual-target system to analyze dust particle impacts and deduce mass and velocity through plasma characteristics. Finally, the TOF mass spectrometer rapidly separates positive ions, contributing to the generation of mass spectra critical for compositional analysis of cosmic dust. This instrumental framework not only enhances our understanding of dust dynamics in the outer solar system but also lays the groundwork for future explorations in planetary science.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
