<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:cirs.co</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Composite Infrared Spectrometer for CO</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2024-10-07</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updates to descriptions and references</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.co</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Calcutt, S.B., F.W. Taylor, P.A.R. Ade, V.G. Kunde, and D.E. Jennings, The
                   Composite Infrared Spectrometer, J. Brit. Interplan Soc., Vol. 45, pp. 811-816,
                   1992.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.CALCUTTETAL1992</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Flasar, F.M., V.G. Kunde, M.M. Abbas, R.K. Achterberg, P. Ade, A. Barucci, B.
                   Bezard, G.L. Bjoraker, J.C. Brasunas, S.B. Calcutt, R. Carlson, C.J. Cesarsky,
                   B.J. Conrath, A. Coradini, R. Courtin, A. Coustenis, S. Edberg, S. Edgington,
                   C. Ferrari, T. Fouchet, D. Gautier, P.J. Gierasch, K. Grossman, P. Irwin, D.E.
                   Jennings, E. Lellouch, A.A. Mamoutkine, A. Marten, J.P. Meyer, C.A. Nixon, G.S.
                   Orton, T.C. Owen, J.C. Pearl, R. Prange, F. Raulin, P.L. Read, P.N. Romani,
                   R.E. Samuelson, M.E. Segura, M.R. Showalter, A.A. Simon-Miller, M.D. Smith,
                   J.R. Spencer, L.J. Spilker, and F.W. Taylor, Exploring the Saturn System in the
                   Thermal Infrared: The Composite Infrared Spectrometer, Space Sci. Rev., Vol.
                   115, pp. 169-297, doi:10.1007/s11214-004-1454-9, 2004.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.FLASARETAL2004B</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Kunde, V.G., P.A.R. Ade, R.D. Barney, D. Bergman, J.-F. Bonnal, R. Borelli, D.
                   Boyd, J.C. Brasunas, G. Brown, S.B. Calcutt, F. Carroll, R. Courtin, J.
                   Cretolle, J.A. Crooke, M.A. Davis, S. Edberg, R. Fettig, M. Flasar, D.A.
                   Glenar, S. Graham, J.G. Hagopian, C.F. Hakun, P.A. Hayes, L. Herath, L. Horn,
                   D.E. Jennings, G. Karpati, C. Kellebenz, B. Lakew, J. Lindsay, J. Lohr, J.J.
                   Lyons, R.J. Martineau, A.J. Martino, M. Matsumura, J. McCloskey, T Melak, G.
                   Michel, A. Morell, C. Mosier, L. Pack, M. Plants, D. Robinson, L. Rodriguez, P.
                   Romani, W.J. Schaefer, S. Schmidt, C. Trujillo, T. Vellacott, K. Wagner, and D.
                   Yun, Cassini Infrared Fourier Spectroscopic Investigation, SPIE Vol. 2803, pp.
                   162-177, doi:10.1117/12.253416, 1996.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.KUNDEETAL1996</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Martin, D.H., and E. Puplett, Polarized Interferometric Spectrometry for the
                   Millimeter and Submillimeter Spectrum, Infrared Physics, Vol 10, pp. 105-109,
                   doi:10.1016/0020-0891(70)90006-0, 1969.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.MARTIN-PUPLETT1969</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Composite Infrared Spectrometer</name>
    <type>Spectrometer</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Infrared Spectrometer-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The Composite Infrared Spectrometer (CIRS) on Cassini is designed to measure infrared emissions from atmospheres, rings, and surfaces over a wavelength range between 7 and 1000 micrometers. Its objectives for Saturn and Titan are to: (1) map the global atmospheric temperature structure; (2) map the global atmospheric gas composition; (3) ascertain global atmospheric haze and cloud distributions; (4) gather information on atmospheric energetic processes; and, (5) search for new atmospheric molecular species. Additional goals are to: (6) map global surface temperatures at Titan; and, (7) to determine the thermal characteristics and composition of Saturn's rings and icy satellites. To accomplish these goals, CIRS consists of a 50.8 cm Cassegrain telescope and three interferometers, a far-infrared, a mid-infrared, and a reference interferometer.
The far-infrared interferometer covers a spectral range from 17-1000 micrometers (10-600/cm). The instrument is a polarizing interferometer with substrate-mounted wire grid polarizers to polarize the radiation and subsequently modulate the polarization. The instrument has a 4.3 milliradian field of view.
The mid-infrared interferometer is of conventional Michelson design and covers a spectral range of 7-17 micrometers (600-1400/cm) in two bands. The first band (9-17 micrometers or 600-1000/cm) is imaged on a 1 x 10 photoconductive HgCdTe detector array. The second band (7-9 micrometers or 1100-1400/cm) is imaged on a 1 x 10 photovoltaic HgCdTe detector array. Each element in each detector array consists of a 0.273 milliradian square pixel.
The reference interferometer provides timing correlation of the science data sampling to the scan mechanism position. Also of a Michelson design, it is used on-axis at the optic center of the mid-infrared interferometer and includes laser diode and LED sources, a quartz beam-splitter/compensator, optics, and a silicon detector.
A 70-80 K cold finger serves as a single-stage passive cooler, radiating to space. There are four commandable set points within the range, but the nominal setting is 80 K. The cold finger has heaters for decontamination and detector annealing.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
