<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ctli="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:issna.co</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Imaging Science Subsystem - Narrow Angle for CO</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Alias_List>
      <Alias>
        <alternate_title>IMAGING SCIENCE SUBSYSTEM - NARROW ANGLE for CO</alternate_title>
      </Alias>
      <Alias>
        <alternate_title>IMAGING SCIENCE SUBSYSTEM - NARROW ANGLE</alternate_title>
      </Alias>
    </Alias_List>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. LIDVID references updated to be LID references. Adding missing "investigation" references. Update instrument type/subtype to use valid CTLI LDD.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.co</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Porco, C.C., R.A. West, S. Squyres, A. McEwen, P. Thomas, C.D. Murray, A.
                   DelGenio, A.P. Ingersoll, T.V. Johnson, G. Neukum, J. Veverka, L. Dones, A.
                   Brahic, J.A. Burns, V. Haemmerle, B. Knowles, D. Dawson, T. Roatsch, K. Beurle,
                   and W. Owen, Cassini Imaging Science: Instrument Characteristics and
                   Capabilities and Anticipated Scientific Investigations at Saturn, Space Science
                   Reviews 115,363-497, 2004.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.PORCOETAL2004</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Imaging Science Subsystem - Narrow Angle for CO</name>
    <Type_List_Area>
      <ctli:Type_List>
        <ctli:type>Imager</ctli:type>
      </ctli:Type_List>
    </Type_List_Area>
    <!--RChen/EN was Camera-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The Cassini Imaging Science Subsystem (ISS) comprises two cameras, a Narrow Angle Camera (NAC) and a Wide Angle Camera (WAC), designed to capture high-quality images of the Saturn system. The NAC is a reflecting telescope known for its resolution, with a focal length of nearly 2002.70 mm and a spectral range from 200 nm to 1100 nm. It features a complex filter assembly with 24 filters for flexibility in imaging and analyzing atmospheric phenomena, including unique UV filters for observations down to 200 nm.

The camera's operational design is centered on precise control and thermal management to preserve image quality, involving passive and active thermal controls, a shutter assembly for light exposure, and a high-sensitivity CCD detector manufactured to enhance UV response by using a protective layer. The overall system requires careful management of power states during operations, including modes for active imaging, low power sleep states, and complete shutdown.

Data captured by the camera is carefully processed, including analog-to-digital conversion, data compression, and encoding to manage the limited storage capacity of the spacecraft. The ISS employs both lossless and lossy compression techniques to reduce data volume while maintaining useful information.

The NAC is equipped with flexibility for different imaging modes and is designed to minimize thermal interference while maintaining image fidelity. It has multiple operational and detector modes to accommodate various scientific goals, with sophisticated data handling to ensure prompt and accurate transmissions back to Earth. Further details on the design and operations of the ISS are provided in accompanying scientific literature.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
