<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:ctli="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:eso-la_silla.ntt.eso_multi</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Eso Multimode Instrument</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Alias_List>
      <Alias>
        <alternate_title>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:eso.ntt.eso_multi</alternate_title>
      </Alias>
      <!-- deprecated LID -->
    </Alias_List>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. Adding missing "telescope" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2021-12-07</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>per RMS, deprecated eso in favor of eso-la_silla</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:telescope:eso-la_silla.ntt</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_telescope</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:telescope:eso-la_silla.ntt</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_telescope</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>Schulz, R., Th. Encrenaz, J.A. Stuewe, and G. Wiedemann. Near-IR emissions in the
upper Jovian atmosphere after SL-9 impact: Indications of possible northern
counterparts, Geophysical Research Letters, 22, 17, 2421-2424, 1995.</reference_text>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Eso Multimode Instrument</name>
    <Type_List_Area>
      <ctli:Type_List>
        <ctli:type>Imager</ctli:type>
      </ctli:Type_List>
    </Type_List_Area>
    <description>The EMMI (Flexible Multi-Mode Instrument) at the New Technology Telescope (NTT) is a sophisticated observational tool designed for a diverse array of astronomical research, encompassing wide-field imaging and high-dispersion echelle spectroscopy. The accompanying manual also introduces SUSI (SUperb Seeing Imager), which enhances EMMI's capabilities, particularly for resolving finer details in astronomical images. This document delineates the operational principles of the NTT's active optics system, the dual-beam structure of EMMI, and the rationale behind its design, which prioritizes high image fidelity while facilitating rapid instrument reconfiguration. Each of EMMI's two optical arms supports distinct observing modes, leveraging advanced CCD technology to adapt to future detector geometries. This flexibility is crucial for capitalizing on the exceptional image quality attainable at La Silla, where sub-arcsecond resolution images necessitated the development of SUSI, allowing seamless transitions between imaging and spectroscopic modes. Detailed specifications for optics, cameras, filters, and calibration processes are provided, alongside guidance on data handling and electronic integration with the NTT's control systems. Initial performance assessments indicate the NTT's pointing accuracy and imaging efficiency, essential for precision astronomical studies. The interplay of technical specifications and user guidelines highlights EMMI's role in advancing observational astronomy, ensuring that researchers can effectively utilize its capabilities for a variety of spectroscopic and imaging projects.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
