<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:esa:psa:context:instrument:hp.ssp</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Surface Science Package for Huygens Probe</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Alias_List>
      <Alias>
        <alternate_title>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:ssp.hp</alternate_title>
      </Alias>
      <!-- deprecated LID -->
    </Alias_List>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. Adding missing "investigation" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2021-02-24</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    Changed inst LIDs from
                      u:n:p:c:i:instID.scID to
                      u:n:p:c:i:scID.instID
                    Changed LIDs from urn:nasa:pds: to urn:esa:psa:
                    And per "Guide toPDS4 Context Products" v1.7,
                    changed all lidvid_reference to lid_reference
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:esa:psa:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.hp</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.unk</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Surface Science Package for Huygens Probe</name>
    <type>Atmospheric Sciences</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Material Property Sensor-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The Surface Science Package (SSP) experiment on the Huygens Probe consisted of nine separate sensors that were designed to measure a wide range of physical properties of Titan's lower atmosphere, surface, and sub-surface. By measuring a number of physical properties of the surface, SSP can constrain the inferred composition and structure of the Titan's near-surface environment. Although the SSP was primarily designed to sense properties of the surface, some of its sensors also made measurements of the atmosphere along the probe's entry path and complemented the data gathered by other experiments on the Huygens probe. An acoustic sounder determined the distance to the surface while descending, which provided information on atmospheric composition and temperature. The force of the impact was recorded by an accelerometer, which was made of a piezoelectric ceramic element that was mounted between a hemispherical titanium alloy head and the pylon shaft. The impact process was sampled at a rate of 10 kHz, giving it an effective depth resolution of 1 mm for a nominal mission impact speed of 5 m s-1. One of the most relevant sensors is the Tiltmeter (TIL) as it provides unambiguous information about the Huygens probe's attitude with respect to the local vertical rather than its acceleration. Two inclinometers are arranged to form an orthogonal x-y pair inside the sensor housing which is attached to the SSP electronics box. During the probe's descent the TIL is sampled at a rate of 1 Hz. Combining the data gained from TIL with relevant information from the Doppler Wind Experiment and Huygens Atmospheric Structure Instrument, one of the important analyses can be conducted, which is the reconstruction of the probe's motion, i.e. its trajectory, attitude, swing and spin, as it falls through the atmosphere and then subsequently during any post-impact dynamics.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
