<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:imu.mer1</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Mars Exploration Rover Opportunity Inertial Measurement Unit</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. LIDVID references updated to be LID references. Adding missing "investigation" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.mars_exploration_rover</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer1</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Crisp, J.A., M. Adler, J.R. Matijevic, S.W. Squyres, R.E. Arvidson, and D.M.
                   Kass, Mars Exploration Rover mission, J. Geophys. Res., 108(E12), 8061,
                   doi:10.1029/2002JE002038, 2003.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.CRISPETAL2003</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Mars Exploration Rover Opportunity Inertial Measurement Unit</name>
    <type>Atmospheric Sciences</type>
    <!-- RChen/EN was Accelerometer-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>Each Mars Exploration Rover (MER) entry capsule contained two LITTON LN-200S Inertial Measurement Units (IMU). One IMU was located within the rover, with the other IMU located on the backshell. The IMU within the rover was not located at the rover's center of mass, and the IMU within the backshell was not located at the backshell's center of mass. Neither of the two IMU's within the entry capsule was located near either the entry shell's center of mass nor the entry shell's spin axis. The entry shell consisted of the heat shield and backshell inside of these two joined components. The four LN-200S units employed in the mission were selected from a larger population for improved stability. These LN-200S IMU's provide three-axis rotation rate and acceleration measurements. The rotation rate is provided by a Fiber Optic Gyro (FOG) sensor, while the accelerations are provided by silicon accelerometers. Each IMU contains three FOGs and three accelerometers, oriented orthogonally to provide measurements in three dimensions simultaneously. The resultant measurements from each of the accelerometers and each of the FOGs is spatially transformed to the center of the IMU prior to being output by the instrument. Each IMU has a mass of 0.75 kg (1.65 pound weight), is ~9 cm by 9 cm in size, and is operated at 12 watts. These LN-200S IMU's have space flight heritage, having been successfully flown on the Clementine mission. The accelerometers within each IMU had a dynamic range of 80g (where g here represents Earth's standard surface gravitational acceleration of 9.80665 meters per second per second) and a resolution of 2.4 milli g's, with a noise level of 1.6 milli g's when sampled at 400 Hz (the nominal instrument sampling rate). The spacecraft could not handle 400 Hz sampling, so the IMU data were summed over 50 measurements, resulting in an 8 Hz sampling by the spacecraft.  This summing has the effect of reducing the effective noise to 300 micro g's, with an effective resolution of 50 micro g's.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
