<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:esa:psa:context:instrument:mex.omega</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Mars Express Orbiter Observatoire Mineralogie, Eau, Glaces, Activite</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Alias_List>
      <Alias>
        <alternate_title>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:omega.mex</alternate_title>
      </Alias>
      <!-- deprecated LID -->
    </Alias_List>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. Adding missing "investigation" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2021-02-24</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    Changed inst LIDs from
                      u:n:p:c:i:instID.scID to
                      u:n:p:c:i:scID.instID
                    Changed LIDs from urn:nasa:pds: to urn:esa:psa:
                    And per "Guide toPDS4 Context Products" v1.7,
                    changed all lidvid_reference to lid_reference
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:esa:psa:context:investigation:mission.mars_express</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:esa:psa:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.mex</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.BIBRINGETAL2002</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Mars Express Orbiter Observatoire Mineralogie, Eau, Glaces, Activite</name>
    <type>Imager</type>
    <type>Spectrometer</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Imaging Spectrometer-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The Mars Express Orbiter (MEX) Observatoire Mineralogie, Eau, Glaces, Activite (OMEGA) is a mapping spectrometer working both in the visible and the infrared spectral ranges.  It is made of two co-aligned channels, one working in the 0.38 to 1.05 micrometers visible and near infrared range (VNIR channel), the other in the 0.93 to 5.1 micrometers short wavelength infrared range (SWIR channel). The data products constitute three-dimensional (X,Y,lambda) image-cubes, with two spatial and one spectral dimensions. The VNIR channel uses a bi- dimensional CCD detector, operated in a pushbroom mode.  Its telescope acquires at once in its focal plane one cross-track line corresponding to the entire 8.8 degrees FOV, defined by an entrance slit; the second dimension of the image is provided by the motion of the S/C. Each line is spectrally dispersed along the columns of the array, the slit being imaged through a concave holographic grating. The SWIR channel operates in the whiskbroom mode: each imaged pixel is acquired at once by an IR telescope; a scanning mirror, in front of the telescope, permits to acquire crosstrack swaths of 16 up to 128 pixels width, for a maximum FOV of 8.8 degrees, thus matching the VNIR FOV, while the S/C motion provides the second spatial dimension. The imaged pixel is focused by the telescope on a slit, followed by a collimator. The beam is then split towards two separated spectrometers, to acquire the IR spectrum of each resolved pixel onto two InSb linear arrays of 128 spectels each, from 0.93 to 2.73 micrometers and from 2.55 to 5.1 micrometers respectively. Each array is cooled down 70K by a dedicated cryocooler, while the entire spectrometer is cooled down 190 K by a conductive link to a passive radiator. The typical IR integration time, defined by the S/C ground track velocity and the spatial sampling chosen, is 5 msec. The corresponding VNIR integration times are 100 to 800 ms, depending on the swath width, thus the altitude. With such integration times, SNR &gt; 100, over the entire spectral range, is the specification. OMEGA is made of two distinct units: - a Camera unit (OMEGA-C) with the VNIR and SWIR spectrographs, their associated electrical devices, and one electronics assembly for the control of the camera. All units are integrated onto a common base plate; its mass is 23.8 kg. - a Main Electronics module (OMEGA-ME), for the data processing and the general management of the instrument; its mass is 5.1 kg.     </description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
