<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:mcs.mro</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Mars Climate Sounder (MCS) for MRO</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2024-10-07</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updates to descriptions and references</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.FOOTETAL2003</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.MCCLEESEETAL1986</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.MCCLEESEETAL1992</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   D. McCleese, J. Schofield, F. Taylor, S. Calcutt, M. Foote, D. Kass, C. Leovy,
                   D. Paige, P. Read, and R. Zurek, 'Mars Climate Sounder: An Investigation of
                   Thermal and Water Vapor Structure, Dust and Condensate Distribution in the
                   Atmosphere, and Energy Balance of the Polar Regions', Journal of Geophysical
                   Research, TBD
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.MCCLEESEETAL2006</description>
    </External_Reference>

  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Mars Climate Sounder</name>
    <type>Spectrometer</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Infrared Spectrometer-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The Mars Climate Sounder (MCS) represents NASA's third attempt to observe Martian weather and monitor the planet's climate using modern infrared remote sensing techniques, including limb sounding. The campaign began in 1986 with the Pressure Modulator Infrared Radiometer (PMIRR) on the Mars Observer mission, which was lost in 1993 during the final pressurization of the spacecraft propulsion system only a few days prior to Mars orbit insertion (MOI). NASA re-selected that scientific investigation, including an enlarged science team and using the same PMIRR instrument design, for another mission, the Mars Climate Orbiter (MCO). Launched in 1998, the MCO spacecraft entered the Martian atmosphere during MOI and was destroyed. NASA selected the same team once more to build the new MCS instrument now onboard the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter (MRO). MCS is not a copy of the PMIRR instrument launched in 1992, as the 1998 PMIRR II was, but is a smaller, lighter instrument with the same scientific objectives as those of the previous two investigations. The Mars Climate Sounder is the first custom designed infrared sounder for systematic meteorological measurements at Mars, using the limb viewing technique to obtain relatively high vertical resolution of better than one pressure scale height. The application of modern technology and the use of new high performance, linear array thermopile detectors with focal plane signal processing and miniature multilayer interference and mesh filters has permitted a fivefold reduction in mass, in part by the elimination of the requirement for cryogenic operation of the focal plane. The compact dimensions of the design allow the entire instrument to be pointed to limb or nadir, for atmospheric and surface mapping respectively, and special patterns to be implemented, for example for mapping over the poles where the complex physics of the energy balance and atmospheric response during the long winter night is to be addressed.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
