<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ctli="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:mcs.mro</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Mars Climate Sounder for MRO</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Alias_List>
      <Alias>
        <alternate_title>MARS CLIMATE SOUNDER</alternate_title>
      </Alias>
      <Alias>
        <alternate_title>MARS CLIMATE SOUNDER for MRO</alternate_title>
      </Alias>
    </Alias_List>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. LIDVID references updated to be LID references. Adding missing "investigation" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.FOOTETAL2003</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.MCCLEESEETAL1986</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.MCCLEESEETAL1992</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   D. McCleese, J. Schofield, F. Taylor, S. Calcutt, M. Foote, D. Kass, C. Leovy,
                   D. Paige, P. Read, and R. Zurek, 'Mars Climate Sounder: An Investigation of
                   Thermal and Water Vapor Structure, Dust and Condensate Distribution in the
                   Atmosphere, and Energy Balance of the Polar Regions', Journal of Geophysical
                   Research, TBD
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.MCCLEESEETAL2006</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Mars Climate Sounder for MRO</name>
    <Type_List_Area>
      <ctli:Type_List>
        <ctli:type>Spectrometer</ctli:type>
      </ctli:Type_List>
    </Type_List_Area>
    <!--RChen/EN was Infrared Spectrometer-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The Mars Climate Sounder (MCS) is an instrument onboard the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter (MRO), designed to acquire systematic meteorological measurements at Mars, using the limb viewing technique to obtain relatively high vertical resolution of better than one pressure scale height. MCS will measure thermal emission from the limb of the atmosphere in nine spectral bands (spectral range of 0.3 to 45 microns) to obtain profiles with a vertical resolution of 5 km, and will invert accurately calibrated measurements of radiance in profiles extending from the surface to an altitude of 80 km to obtain vertical profiles of atmospheric temperature, water vapor abundance, and dust and condensate opacities. The entire MCS optical bench is articulated in two axes in order that the limb as well as the nadir can be observed. The range of articulation is 270 degrees in both azimuth and elevation axes providing views of the full hemisphere beneath the nadir-pointed payload platform. The two identical MCS telescopes (f/1.7) are differentiated primarily by their focal planes. Telescope A has a focal plane with six spectral channels, which are in the visible and mid-IR range and are defined spectrally by optical interference filters mounted over six, 21-element linear thermopile detector arrays. The telescope B focal plane has three far-infrared spectral channels, defined spectrally by conductive mesh filters mounted over three detector arrays. Each MCS focal plane assembly consists of a detector chip, focal plane signal processing chips, and a bandpass filter assembly, all mounted on a focal plane block. The spectral passbands of MCS are defined using individual spectral filters mounted in metal frames in front of each of the 9 detector arrays. For telescope A, the five mid-infrared multilayer interference filters in the focal plane cover the 11.8 to 22.2 microns wavelength range. The three far infrared filters in focal plane B consist of stacks of mesh filters. Thermal stability of all the spectral filters is critical.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
