<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:chemcam_rmi.msl</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Mars Science Laboratory Curiosity Rover Chemistry Camera Remote Micro-Imager</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. LIDVID references updated to be LID references. Adding missing "investigation" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.mars_science_laboratory</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.msl</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Maurice, S., R.C. Wiens, et al., The ChemCam instrument suite on the Mars
                   Science Laboratory (MSL) Rover: Science objectives and mast unit description,
                   Space Sci. Rev. doi:10.1007/s11214-012-9912-2, 2012.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.MAURICEETAL2012</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Wiens, R.C., S. Maurice, et al., The ChemCam instrument suite on the Mars
                   Science Laboratory (MSL) Rover: Body unit and combined system tests, Space Sci.
                   Rev. doi:10.1007/s11214-012-9902-4, 2012.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.WIENSETAL2012A</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Wiens, R.C., et al., Pre-flight calibration and initial data processing for the
                   ChemCam laser-induced breakdown spectroscopy instrument on the Mars Science
                   Laboratory rover, Spectrochimica Acta Part B: Atomic Spectroscopy,
                   doi:10.1016/j.sab.2013.02.003, 2013.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.WIENSETAL2013</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Mars Science Laboratory Curiosity Rover Chemistry Camera Remote Micro-Imager</name>
    <type>Imager</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Camera-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The Mars Science Laboratory (MSL) Curiosity Rover ChemCam instrument suite includes both the LIBS (Laser Induced Breakdown Spectrometer) and the RMI (Remote Micro-Imager) components. The ChemCam RMI instrument provides context imaging with sub-millimeter resolution comparable to a close-up camera, but at metric distances. The instrument suite consists of two major sections, the Mast Unit, housing the laser, RMI, telescope, and associated electronics, and the Body Unit, consisting of an optical demultiplexer, three spectrometers, the thermo-electric cooler, CCD electronics, spectrometer electronics, the data processing unit (DPU), and the low-voltage power supply.  The ChemCam mast unit is contained in the remote warm electronics box (RWEB) at the top of the rover's mast. The body unit is located in the rover body, attached to the rover accommodation mounting plate (RAMP). Besides the mast and body units, there are two other sections of the instrument. A fiber optic cable transmits the plasma light between the two ChemCam units.  Finally, included on the rover deck is a calibration target assembly.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
