<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model
    href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
    schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model
    href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch"
    schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context
    xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
    xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" 
    xmlns:ctli="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
    xsi:schemaLocation="
        http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd 
        http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:ody.themis</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>Thermal Emission Imaging System (THEMIS) for ODY</title>
        <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
        <Alias_List>
            <Alias>
                <alternate_title>THEMIS</alternate_title>
            </Alias>
            <Alias>
                <alternate_title>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:themis.ody</alternate_title>  <!-- deprecated LID -->
            </Alias>
        </Alias_List>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2023-09-15</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description> Update to ody.themis and set alias to the original themis.ody. 
                    Updated to PDS4_PDS_1F00.xsd to allow for DOI and added DOI to reference. 
                    And per "Guide to PDS4 Context Products" v1.8, changed all lidvid_reference to lid_reference.
                    Added and then updated (2024-06-05) ctli for Instrument class, type = Imaging Spectrometer  
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2024-10-02</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.1</version_id>
                <description>
                    Where applicable, updated version, title, name
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.ody</lid_reference>
            <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Christensen, P. R., Calibration Report for the Thermal Emission Imaging
                   System (THEMIS) for the Mars 2001 Odyssey Mission, September 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CHRISTENSEN2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <doi>10.1023/B:SPAC.0000021008.16305.94</doi>
            <reference_text>
                   Christensen, P. R., B. M. Jakosky, H. H. Kieffer, M. C. Malin, H. Y.
                   McSween, Jr., K. Nealson, G. L. Mehall, S. H. Silverman, S. Ferry, and M.
                   Caplinger, (2004), The Thermal Emission Imaging System (THEMIS) for the Mars 2001
                   Odyssey Mission, Space Science Reviews volume 110, pages85–120.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CHRISTENSENETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>

    <Instrument>
        <name>Thermal Emission Imaging System</name>
        <Type_List_Area>
            <ctli:Type_List>
                <ctli:type>Imaging Spectrometer</ctli:type>
            </ctli:Type_List>
        </Type_List_Area>
        <description>
            The THEMIS flight instrument is a combined infrared and visible
            multi-spectral pushbroom imager.  It has a
            12-cm effective aperature telescope and co-aligned infrared and
            visible area arrays.  The imaging system is comprised of a
            three-mirror anastigmat telescope in a rugged enclosure, a
            visible/infrared beamsplitter, a silicon focal plane for visible
            detection, and a microbolometer for infrared detection.  A major
            feature of this instrument is the use of an uncooled IR
            microbolometer array operated at ambient temperature, eliminating
            the need for complex passive or active cryogenic coolers.  A small
            thermal electric cooler is used to stabilize the detector
            temperature to 0.001K.  A calibration flag, the only moving part in
            the instrument, provides thermal calibration and a DC restore
            capability, and will also be used to protect the detectors from
            unintentional direct illumination from the Sun when the instrument
            is not in use.  The electronics provide digital data collection and
            processing as well as the instrument control and data interface to
            the spacecraft.  Infrared data will be collected in 9 wavelengths
            centered from 6.6 to 15.0 microns at 100 meter per pixel resolution;
            the 6.6 micron band is collected twice to result in a 10 band image.
            Visible data will be collected in 5 spectral bands at a resolution
            of 18 meters per pixel.  The instrument weighs 11.2 kg, is 29 cm by
            37 cm by 55 cm in size, and consumes an orbital average power of
            14W.
            </description>
    </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
