<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:ctli="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:rss.orex</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>OSIRIS-REx Radio Science (Telecom) Subsystem</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. Adding missing "investigation" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2021-09-10</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>First version of the context product to be archived with the PDS.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.orex</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.orex</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <doi>10.1007/s11214-018-0521-6</doi>
      <reference_text>
                E.B. Bierhaus, B.C. Clark, J.W. Harris, K.S. Payne, R.D. Dubisher, D.W. Wurts, R.A. Hund, R.M. Kuhns, 
                T.M. Linn, J.L. Wood, A.J. May, J.P. Dworkin, E. Beshore, D.S. Lauretta and the OSIRIS-REx Team, 
                The OSIRIS-REx Touch-and-Go Sample Acquisition Mechanism (TAGSAM) and Flight System, Space Science Reviews,
                214:107, 2018.
            </reference_text>
      <description>
                This paper describes the OSIRIS-REx spacecraft and its main subsystems. The paragraph on telecommunications gives high-level information on the 
                radio, including data downlink strategy and data rates.
            </description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <doi>10.1007/s11214-018-0480-y</doi>
      <reference_text>McMahon, J.W., Scheeres, D.J., Hesar, S.G., Farnocchia, D., Chesley, S., Lauretta, D. The OSIRIS-REx Radio Science Experiment at Bennu.
            Space Sci Rev 214, 43 (2018).</reference_text>
      <description>
                This paper describes the originally planned OSIRIS-REx Radio Science investigation of the asteroid Bennu
                with a primary goal of estimating the mass and gravity field of the asteroid. There  is very little discussion
                of the spacecraft radio instrumentation in the paper.The spacecraft conducted proximity operations around Bennu for over 1 year, during 
                which time radiometric tracking data, optical landmark tracking images, and altimetry data were obtained that could be used to make these estimates.
                The Radio Science team was also responsible for estimating the surface accelerations, surface slopes, constraints on the internal
                density distribution of Bennu, the rotational state of Bennu to confirm YORP estimates, and the ephemeris of 
                Bennu that incorporates a detailed model of the Yarkovsky effect. 
            </description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <doi>10.1126/sciadv.abc3350</doi>
      <reference_text>D. J. Scheeres, A. S. French, P. Tricarico, S. R. Chesley, Y. Takahashi, D. Farnocchia, J. W. McMahon, D. N. Brack, A. B. Davis,
             R.-L. Ballouz, E. R. Jawin, B. Rozitis, J. P. Emery, A. J. Ryan, R. S. Park, B. P. Rush, N. Mastrodemos, B. M. Kennedy, J. Bellerose, D. P. Lubey,
             D. Velez, A. T. Vaughan, J. M. Leonard, J. Geeraert, B. Page, P. Antreasian, E. Mazarico, K. Getzandanner, D. Rowlands, M. C. Moreau,J. Small,
             D. E. Highsmith, S. Goossens, E. E. Palmer, J. R. Weirich, R. W. Gaskell, O. S. Barnouin, M. G. Daly, J. A. Seabrook, M. M. Al Asad, L. C. Philpott,
             C. L. Johnson, C. M. Hartzell, V. E. Hamilton, P. Michel, K. J. Walsh, M. C. Nolan, D. S. Lauretta; Heterogeneous mass distribution of the 
             rubble-pile asteroid (101955) Bennu. Science Advances, doi:10.1126/sciadv.abc3350, 2020.</reference_text>
      <description>
                The asteroid (101955) Bennu has a heterogeneous internal mass distribution with an underdense center and equatorial bulge.
                The gravity field of a small body provides insight into its internal mass distribution. We used two approaches to measure the gravity 
                field of the rubble-pile asteroid (101955) Bennu: (i) tracking and modeling the spacecraft in orbit about the asteroid and (ii) tracking
                and modeling pebble-sized particles naturally ejected from Bennu’s surface into sustained orbits. These approaches yield statistically
                consistent results up to degree and order 3, with the particle-based field being statistically significant up to degree and order 9. 
                Comparisons with a constant-density shape model show that Bennu has a heterogeneous mass distribution. These deviations can be modeled
                with lower densities at Bennu’s equatorial bulge and center. The lower-density equator is consistent with recent migration and
                redistribution of material. The lower-density center is consistent with a past period of rapid rotation, either from a previous 
                Yarkovsky-O’Keefe-Radzievskii-Paddack cycle or arising during Bennu’s accretion following the disruption of its parent body.
            </description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <doi>10.1029/2019JE006363</doi>
      <reference_text>S. R. Chesley, A. S. French, A. B. Davis, R. A. Jacobson, M. Brozović, D. Farnocchia, S. Selznick, A. J. Liounis, C. W. Hergenrother,
            M. C. Moreau, J. Pelgrift, E. Lessac-Chenen, J. L. Molaro, R. S. Park, B. Rozitis, D. J. Scheeres, Y. Takahashi, D. Vokrouhlický, C. W. V. Wolner,
            C. Adam, B. J. Bos, E. J. Christensen, J. P. Emery, J. M. Leonard, J. W. McMahon, M. C. Nolan, F. C. Shelly, D. S. Lauretta, Trajectory Estimation for
            Particles Observed in the Vicinity of (101955) Bennu, JGR Planets,  https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JE006363, 2020.</reference_text>
      <description>
                The Origins, Spectral Interpretation, Resource Identification, Security, Regolith Explorer (OSIRIS-REx) mission discovered that near-Earth 
                asteroid (101955) Bennu is periodically ejecting small particles from its surface, placing it in the uncommon class of “active asteroids.” 
                We linked together individual detections of ejected particles and used numerical models of the forces acting on them to ascertain their 
                trajectories and fates. We found that most particles have suborbital trajectories, meaning they fall back to Bennu's surface shortly after  
                being ejected, but some orbit Bennu for days at a time, and some escape directly into space. From the particle trajectories, we are able to
                estimate their sizes (comparable to pebbles, from a few millimeters to a few centimeters in diameter) and shapes (probably flake like). Their
                trajectories also make it possible to estimate Bennu's gravity field more precisely than spacecraft measurements and help shed light on the 
                possible causes of the ejections.
            </description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Radio Science (Telecom) Subsystem</name>
    <Type_List_Area>
      <ctli:Type_List>
        <ctli:type>Radio Science</ctli:type>
      </ctli:Type_List>
    </Type_List_Area>
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>
            The spacecraft element of the OSIRIS-REx radio science instrument was the 
            onboard telecommunications subsystem.  It included a pair of cross-strapped redundant 
            General Dynamics Small Deep Space Transponder Group Buy III X/X transponders, two cross-strapped 100-watt traveling wave tube
            amplifiers, and four antennas.  Cross-strapping protected the mission against single point failures in the telecom subsystem.
             
            The antenna location in reference to the s/c frame are defined as follows:
               -  the HGA frame is nominally rotated from the s/c frame by +90 degrees about Y, then by -150 about Z.
               -  the MGA frame is nominally rotated from the s/c frame by +106 degrees about Y.
               -  the LGA_PX frame is nominally rotated from the s/c frame by +135 degrees about Y.
               -  the LGA_MX frame is nominally rotated from the s/c frame by -45 degrees about Y.
            Turnaround Ratio – 840/749
            Nominal uplink and downlink frequencies – Nominal Rx Freq – 7188.499990 MHz, Nominal Tx Freq – 8445.767679 MHz
            The transponder carrier delay variation is +/- 3 ns  

            The radio science investigation used all available data over the course of the mission.
      </description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
