<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1N00.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1N00_2100.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xmlns:ctli="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1N00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1N00_2100.xsd">

  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:pvmp.sp-night.dlbi</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.0</version_id>
    <title>DIFFERENTIAL LONG BASE LINE INTERFEROMETER for PIONEER VENUS SMALL PROBE (NIGHT)</title>
    <information_model_version>1.23.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-04-01</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
              Initial creation
            </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>

  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.pvmp.sp-night</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.pioneer_venus</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <doi>10.1126/science.203.4382.805</doi>
      <reference_text> Counselman, C. C., III, et al., Wind velocities on Venus: Vector
        determination by radio interferometry, Science, 203, No. 4382, 805-806, Feb. 1979.
      </reference_text>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <doi>10.1029/JA085iA13p08026</doi>
      <reference_text> Counselman, C. C., III, et al., Zonal and meridional circulation of the lower
        atmosphere of Venus determined by radio interferometry, J. Geophys. Res., 85, No. A13,
        8026-8031, Dec. 1980. </reference_text>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <doi>10.1007/BF02186463</doi>
      <reference_text> Colin, L., Ed., and D. M. Hunten, Ed., Pioneer Venus experiment descriptions,
        Space Sci. Rev., 20, No. 4, 451-525, June 1977. </reference_text>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>

  <Instrument>
    <name>PIONEER VENUS SMALL PROBE (NIGHT) DIFFERENTIAL LONG BASE LINE INTERFEROMETER</name>
    <Type_List_Area>
      <ctli:Type_List>
        <ctli:type>Radio Science</ctli:type>
        <ctli:subtype>Interferometer</ctli:subtype>
      </ctli:Type_List>
    </Type_List_Area>
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>

    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>

    <description>

      This experiment involved applying differential long-baseline interferometry
      techniques to the radio signals from the entry probes and bus in order to infer or
      place upper limits on wind speeds in the lower atmosphere. These results were used
      in modeling the circulation patterns of Venus' atmosphere.

      As the four probes descended, the Pioneer Venus Probe Bus followed a well-defined
      ballistic trajectory above the atmosphere that was accurately known with respect to
      the planet's surface. Probe velocities were measured relative to the Bus.
      Additionally, four ground stations on Earth simultaneously tracked the four probes.
      These were the 64-meter dish Goldstone and Canberra Deep Space Network (DSN)
      stations, and the 9-meter dish Santiago (Chile) and Guam Spaceflight Tracking And
      Data Network (STDN) stations. They covered passbands of 2291 to 2293 MHz to receive
      signals from all four probes and the bus simultaneously. The Doppler frequency
      shifts of the received 13 cm (S-band) signals gave the component of the velocity
      vector along the Earth-spacecraft line of sight. The differential long-baseline
      interferometry was used to find the other two components of the velocity vector of
      each probe.

      Measurements of the temperature and pressure taken by other instruments as the
      probes descended were used with the interferometry results. Data taken prior to
      probe entry were used, where feasible, to infer characteristics of Venus' gravity
      field for use with probe entry operations as well as in later scientific evaluation.
      Deviations of the probe trajectories from the mathematical model of their
      trajectories in a still atmosphere were attributed to winds. Overall uncertainties
      were estimated at 10 cm/s.

      The magnitude of the wind velocity was found to be about 1 meter/s or less near the
      surface of the planet and about 100 meters/s near 65-km altitude at all four probe
      locations. High wind shear was measured centered at altitudes of 15, 45, and 60 km.
      The wind velocity was uniformly directed very close to due west, except within a few
      km of the surface.

        </description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
