<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ctli="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:pvo.oims</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>2.1</version_id>
    <title>ION MASS SPECTROMETER (OIMS) for PIONEER VENUS</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>2.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. Adding missing "investigation" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2020-08-26</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2024-04-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>2.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    Updated to IM 1.20.0.0
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.pioneer_venus</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.pvo</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Brinton, H.C., L.R. Scott, M.W. Pharo, III, and J.T.C. Coulson, The
                   Bennett ion-mass spectrometer on Atmosphere Explorer-C and -E, Radio Sci.,
                   vol. 8, 323, 1973.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.BRINTONETAL1973</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Taylor, H.A., Jr., H.C. Brinton, S.J. Bauer, R.E. Hartle, T.M. Donahue,
                   P.A. Cloutier, F.C. Michel, R.E. Daniell, Jr., B.H. Blackwell, Ionosphere
                   of Venus: First observations of the dayside ion composition near dawn and
                   dusk, Science, vol. 203, 752, 1979.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.TAYLORETAL1979C</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Taylor, H.A., Jr., H.C. Brinton, S.J. Bauer, R.E. Hartle, P.A. Cloutier,
                   F.C. Michel, R.E. Daniell, Jr., T.M. Donahue, R.C. Maehl, Ionosphere of
                   Venus: First observations of the effects of dynamics on the dayside ion
                   composition, Science, vol. 203, 755, 1979.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.TAYLORETAL1979D</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>ION MASS SPECTROMETER (OIMS) for PIONEER VENUS</name>
    <Type_List_Area>
      <ctli:Type_List>
        <ctli:type>Mass Spectrometer</ctli:type>
      </ctli:Type_List>
    </Type_List_Area>
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>
 
    INSTRUMENT OVERVIEW
    ===================
        
           Using the Pioneer Venus Orbiter Ion Mass Spectrometer (OIMS), composition and concentration of thermal positive ions 
           in the ionosphere of Venus were determined and interpreted in terms of vertical and horizontal components. These provided 
           information on provided information on the solar wind interaction with Venus, upper atmosphere photochemistry, and the 
           mass and heat transport characteristics of the atmosphere. The instrument used was a Bennett radio-frequency mass spectrometer 
           based on the design of those flown on OGO and Atmospheric Explorer satellites. A mass range of 1-56 amu was covered with a 
           variety of automatic scan-search modes available.
    
            Identical Ion Mass Spectrometers were mounted on the Pioneer Venus Orbiter and the Probe Bus. Each spectrometer, with a mass 
            of 3.0 kg, consisted of two parts, an analyzer tube and an electronics package. The electronics package held printed circuit 
            boards inside a machined magnesium housing mounted inside the spacecraft. The package contained low- and high-gain pre-amplifiers, 
            amplifiers, a log A/D converter, an RF generator, voltage regulator, command and control, and data handling. It uses 1.5 W of power, 
            and functions to supply RF and DC potentials to the ion analyzer tube; detect and amplify ion current flowing to the collectors; 
            digitize, process, and format data for telemetry; configure the sensor for subsequent measurements; and decode and implement commands.
    
            The analyzer tube is a hollow cylinder of aluminum containing a series of knitted tungsten mesh grids and gold-plated aluminum spacers. 
            These are backed by a supressor, a low-gain collector and a high-gain collector. At the head of the tube is a guard ring and an 
            accelerating voltage. The analyzer can be set to measure any of 16 common ion masses from 1 to 56 amu (1, 2, 4, 8, 12, 14, 16, 17, 
            18, 24, 28, 30, 32, 40, 44, and 56 amu). It also has the ability to produce simulated ion currents for calibration.
    
            The instrument operated with repeated explore/adapt cycles, each 6.3 seconds in duration. The first 1.8 seconds of the cycle is the 
            explore portion, which consists of measuring each of the 16 pre-selected masses for approximately 0.1 second each. In the 4.5 
            second adapt portion of the cycle, up to 8 ions that are found to be present in the explore portion are measured repeatedly. The 
            ion current values from each measurement are sampled, held for A/D conversion, and transfered to telemetry storage registers.
        </description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
