<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ctli="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:esa:psa:context:instrument:uly.urap</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Unified Radio and Plasma Wave Experiment for ULY</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Alias_List>
      <Alias>
        <alternate_title>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:urap.uly</alternate_title>
      </Alias>
      <!-- deprecated LID -->
      <Alias>
        <alternate_title>UNIFIED RADIO AND PLASMA WAVE EXPERIMENT</alternate_title>
      </Alias>
      <Alias>
        <alternate_title>UNIFIED RADIO AND PLASMA WAVE EXPERIMENT for ULY</alternate_title>
      </Alias>
    </Alias_List>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-02</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. Adding missing "investigation" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2021-02-24</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    Changed inst LIDs from
                      u:n:p:c:i:instID.scID to
                      u:n:p:c:i:scID.instID
                    Changed LIDs from urn:nasa:pds: to urn:esa:psa:
                    And per "Guide toPDS4 Context Products" v1.7,
                    changed all lidvid_reference to lid_reference
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:esa:psa:context:investigation:mission.ulysses</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:esa:psa:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.uly</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   MacDowall, R.J., R.A. Hess, N. Lin, G. Thejappa, A. Balogh, and J.L. Phillips,
                   Ulysses spacecraft observations of radio and plasma waves: 1991:1995, submitted
                   to Astron. Astrophys., 1996.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.MACDOWALLETAL1996</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Stone, R.G., J.L. Bougeret, J. Caldwell, P. Canu, Y. de Conchy, N.
                   Cornilleau-Wehrlin, M.D. Desch, J. Fainberg, K. Goetz, M.L. Goldstein, C.C.
                   Harvey, S. Hoang, R. Howard, M.L. Kaiser, P.J. Kellogg, B. Klein, R. Knoll, A.
                   Lecacheux, D. Lengyel-Frey, R.J. MacDowall, R. Manning, C.A. Meetre, A. Meyer,
                   N. Monge, S. Monson, G. Nicol, M.J. Reiner, J.L. Steinberg, E. Torres, C. de
                   Villedary, F. Wouters, and P. Zarka, The Unified Radio and Plasma Wave
                   Investigation, Astron. Astrophys. Suppl. Ser. 92, 291-316, 1992.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.STONEETAL1992A</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Unified Radio and Plasma Wave Experiment for ULY</name>
    <type>Plasma Wave Spectrometer</type>
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The Ulysses Unifield Radio and Plasma Wave (URAP) experiment is designed to advance our understanding of radio and plasma phenomena in the heliosphere and Jovian magnetosphere. This study presents two primary objectives: first, to ascertain the direction, angular size, and polarization of radio sources, thereby enabling remote sensing capabilities in these regions; and second, to conduct an in-depth examination of local wave phenomena influencing ambient plasma transport coefficients. The ability to track solar radio bursts provides critical three-dimensional insights into the large-scale magnetic field configurations that facilitate the propagation of solar exciter particles. Additionally, URAP's investigations into Jovian radio emissions are expected to enhance our knowledge regarding the source localization and generation mechanisms of planetary radio emissions. The experimental setup features a sophisticated array of sensors, including a 72.5 m electric field antenna situated in the spin plane, a 7.5 m electric field monopole aligned with the spin axis, and dual orthogonal search coil magnetic antennas. This array is optimized to cover a broad frequency range from direct current (DC) to 1 MHz. Specific investigative needs are addressed through various receivers, including a relaxation sounder that delivers precise measurements of electron density. Observational results from URAP have elucidated both the capabilities and limitations of its instruments, documenting a range of phenomena such as solar bursts, auroral kilometric radiation, Jovian bursts, as well as plasma waves including Langmuir waves, ion acoustic-like noise, and whistlers. These findings contribute significantly to our comprehension of wave-particle interactions in the solar wind and within the environment of Jupiter.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
