<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:esa:psa:context:instrument:uly.udds</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Ulysses Dust Detection System for ULY</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Alias_List>
      <Alias>
        <alternate_title>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:udds.uly</alternate_title>
      </Alias>
      <!-- deprecated LID -->
    </Alias_List>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2021-02-24</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    Changed inst LIDs from
                      u:n:p:c:i:instID.scID to
                      u:n:p:c:i:scID.instID
                    Changed LIDs from urn:nasa:pds: to urn:esa:psa:
                    And per "Guide toPDS4 Context Products" v1.7,
                    changed all lidvid_reference to lid_reference
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2024-10-07</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updates to descriptions and references</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:esa:psa:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.uly</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:esa:psa:context:investigation:mission.ulysses</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Baguhl, M., E. Gruen, E., D. Linkert, G. Linkert, and N. Siddique,
                   Identification of 'small' dust impacts in the Ulysses dust detector data,
                   Planetary and Space Science 41, 1085-1098, 1993.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.BAGUHLETAL1993</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Goller, J.R., and Gruen E., Calibration of the Galileo/Ulysses dust detectors
                   with different projectile materials and at varying impact angle, Planet. Space
                   Sci. 37, 1197-1206, 1989.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.GOLLER-GRUEN1989</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Gruen, E., H. Fechtig, J. Kissel, D. Linkert, D. Maas, J.A.M. McDonnell, G.E.
                   Morfill, G. Schwehm, H.A. Zook, and R. H. Giese, The Ulysses dust experiment,
                   Astron Astrophys. Suppl. Ser. 92, 411-423, 1992.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.GRUENETAL1992B</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Gruen, E., M. Baguhl, N. Divine, H. Fechtig, D.P. Hamilton, and 14 others, Two
                   years of Ulysses dust data, Planet. Space Sci, 43, 971-999, 1995.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.GRUENETAL1995A</description>
    </External_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Gruen, E., M. Baguhl, D.P. Hamilton, J. Kissel, D. Linkert, and 2 others,
                   Reduction of Galileo and Ulysses dust data, Planet. Space Sci, 43, 941-951,
                   1995.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.GRUENETAL1995C</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>Ulysses Dust Detection System</name>
    <type>Dust</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Dust Detector-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The objective of the Ulysses dust experiment is to investigate the physical and dynamical properties of small dust particles as a function of ecliptic latitude and heliocentric distance, and the study of their interrelation with interplanetary/interstellar phenomena.  The parameters to be determined include the mass, speed, flight direction and electric charge of individual particles.  Specific objectives are: (1) to determine the impact rate, size frequency, and the distribution of flight directions and electric charges of interplanetary dust particles; (2) to classify particle orbits into bound orbits around the Sun or hyperbolic orbits leaving or entering the solar system; (3) to study the distributions of orbital elements (semi-major axis, eccentricity, inclination ) of particles in bound orbits; (4) to determine as functions of heliocentric distance and ecliptic latitude the spatial density of the interplanetary large particle population which generally moves in bound orbits around the sun, and to determine the relative significance of comets and asteroids as sources for these zodiacal dust particles; (5) to measure the flux and velocity of particles coming in hyperbolic orbits from the general direction of the Sun; (6) to identify interstellar dust particles and perform direct measurements of the spatial density, heliocentric distribution, velocity and mass of interstellar grains traversing the solar system; (7) to observe enhancements of cometary dust particles during the transit of the spacecraft through the plane of a comet's orbit; (8) to investigate the spatial density of dust particles within the asteroid belt and determine the amount of dust produced by collisions in the asteroid belt; (9) to investigate the influence of the Jovian gravitational field on the interplanetary dust population; (10) to measure electric charges of dust particles and establish the relationship of these charges to the properties of the ambient plasma (plasma density, energy spectrum), the solar radiation spectrum and magnetic fields</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
