<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1N00.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1N00_2100.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
  xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ctli="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1N00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1N00_2100.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:v13.ep</logical_identifier>  
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ENERGETIC PARTICLES, MSU-TASPD, for VENERA 13</title>
        <information_model_version>1.23.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2024-12-20</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    Initial creation
                </description>
             </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
 
    <Reference_List>
        <!-- <Internal_Reference> -->
        <!--     <lid_reference>the soviets</lid_reference> -->
        <!--     <reference_type>instrument_to_agency</reference_type> -->
        <!-- </Internal_Reference> -->
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.venera_13</lid_reference>
            <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.v13</lid_reference>
            <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
 
    <Instrument>
        <name>VENERA 13 ENERGETIC PARTICLES, MSU-TASPD</name>  
        <Type_List_Area>
            <ctli:Type_List>
                <ctli:type>Charged Particle Detector</ctli:type>
            </ctli:Type_List>
        </Type_List_Area> 
        <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
 
        <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
 
        <description>
The Energetic Particles Experiment on Venera 13 was the Soviet ASP-18M suite
of detectors. It was designed to monitor the flux of charged particles of
medium energies during cruise and Venus flyby. The ASP-18M suite consisted of
five sensors: four solid state detectors and one gas-discharge
(Geiger-Mueller) detector. The sensors measured the flux continuously. Stored
in the spacecraft memory, the data would be transmitted at 20- or 80-minute
resolution depending on the detector. The instrument data run from 31 October
1981, the day after launch, through Venus flyby on 1 March 1982, and continue
until 12 April 1983.

Sensor D1 was a Solid State Detector (SSD) consisting of a 420 micron thick
plate of silicon covered by thin foil and placed under a collimator with a
hole in the shape of a cone, and a pulse-amplitude analyzer. It was designed
to continuously measure the flux of protons and alpha particles coming from
within 30 degrees of the sunward direction with a geometric factor of 0.09 cm2
sr in three channels. The main spacecraft axis was sunward directed with 10 -
15 degree precision. Channel 1 counted protons in the energy range from 1.9 to
2.5 MeV and alpha-particles of energy 3.9 to 4.4 MeV. Channel 2 counted
protons from 2.5 - 4.6 MeV and alpha particles from 4.4 - 6.1 MeV. Channel 3
counted protons from 4.6 - 8.0 MeV and alpha particles from 6.1 - 8.8 MeV. The
time resolution of the data was 80 minutes.

Sensor D2 was an SSD consisting of a 420 micron thick plate of silicon covered
by thin foil and placed under a collimator with a hole in the shape of a cone,
and a pulse-amplitude analyzer. It was designed to continuously measure the
flux of protons and alpha particles coming from within 30 degrees of the
anti-sunward direction with a geometric factor of 0.09 cm2 sr in three
channels. The main spacecraft axis was sunward directed with 10 - 15 degree
precision. Channel 1 counted protons in the energy range from 1.9 to 2.5 MeV
and alpha-particles of energy 3.9 to 4.4 MeV. Channel 2 counted protons from
2.5 - 4.6 MeV and alpha particles from 4.4 - 6.1 MeV. Channel 3 counted
protons from 4.6 - 8.0 MeV and alpha particles from 6.1 - 8.8 MeV. The time
resolution of the data was 80 minutes.

Sensor D3 was an SBM-20 series gas discharge (Geiger-Mueller) counter, a thin
1 cm diameter, 9 cm long cylinder. It was mounted inside the wall of the
spacecraft on the sunward facing side. It had minimal shielding (~1 g/cm2
aluminum) provided by the spacecraft skin for particles coming from the
direction of the Sun (geometric factor 13 cm2 sr), giving a threshold of
proton energy of >30 MeV and electron energy of >2 MeV. For protons coming
from directions other than the Sun, the body of the spacecraft provided
shielding requiring an energy threshold of 500 MeV. These particles had a
geometric factor of 54 cm2 sr. The flux intensity in particles per second was
measured continuously for all species. Time resolution of the data was 20
minutes.

Sensor D4 was an SSD consisting of a 50 micron thick plate of silicon covered
by thin foil and placed under a collimator with a hole in the shape of a cone,
and a pulse-amplitude analyzer. It was designed to continuously measure the
flux of protons and alpha particles coming from within 30 degrees of the
sunward direction with a geometric factor of 0.09 cm2 sr. It measured protons
with energy 1.5 to 3.5 MeV and alpha-particles with energy 3.7 to 65 MeV. Time
resolution of the data was 20 minutes.

Sensor D5 was an SSD consisting of a 50 micron thick plate of silicon covered
by thin foil and placed under a collimator with a hole in the shape of a cone,
and a pulse-amplitude analyzer. It was designed to continuously measure the
flux of protons and alpha particles coming from within 30 degrees of the
anti-sunward direction with a geometric factor of 0.09 cm2 sr. It measured
protons with energy 1.5 to 3.5 MeV and alpha-particles with energy 3.7 to 65
MeV. Time resolution of the data was 20 minutes.
 
The Principal Investigator for this experiment was Dr. Nick Kontor of Moscow
State University.
        </description>
    </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
