<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:individual.titan-material-database</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Titan Material Database - Material Properties of Organic Liquids, Ices, and Hazes on Titan</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2023-05-25</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>
                    Initial setup for this investigation.
                </description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2024-10-22</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. Adding missing "agency" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:agency:agency.nasa</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>investigation_to_agency</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:target:satellite.saturn.titan</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>investigation_to_target</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:target:laboratory_analog.saturn.titan</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>investigation_to_target</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <doi>10.48550/arXiv.2210.01394</doi>
      <reference_text>Yu, Xinting, Yue Yu, Julia Garver, Jialin Li, Abigale Hawthorn, Ella Sciamma-O'Brien, Xi Zhang, and Erika Barth (2023). Material Properties of Organic Liquids, Ices, and Hazes on Titan, </reference_text>
      <description>Citation of the official published version of the paper.</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Investigation>
    <name>Material Properties of Organic Liquids, Ices, and Hazes on Titan</name>
    <type>Individual Investigation</type>
    <start_date>2022</start_date>
    <stop_date>2023</stop_date>
    <description>
            Titan has a diverse range of materials in its atmosphere and on its surface: the simple organics that reside in various phases (gas, liquid, ice) 
            and the solid complex refractory organics that form Titan's haze layers. These materials all actively participate in various physical processes 
            on Titan, and many material properties are found to be important in shaping these processes. Future in-situ exploration on Titan would likely 
            encounter a range of materials, and a comprehensive database to archive the material properties of all possible material candidates will be needed. 
            Here we summarize several important material properties of the organic liquids, ices, and the refractory hazes on Titan that are available in the 
            literature and/or that we have computed. These properties include thermodynamic properties (phase change points, sublimation and vaporization 
            saturation vapor pressure, and latent heat), physical property (density), and surface properties (liquid surface tensions and solid surface 
            energies). We have developed a new database to provide a repository for these data and make them available to the science community. These data 
            can be used as inputs for various theoretical models to interpret current and future remote sensing and in-situ atmospheric and surface 
            measurements on Titan. The material properties of the simple organics may also be applicable to giant planets and icy bodies in the outer solar 
            system, interstellar medium, protoplanetary disks, and exoplanets.
        </description>
  </Investigation>
</Product_Context>
