<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:telescope:eso-chajnantor.alma</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>Atacama Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA)</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2025-01-07</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. Adding missing "telescope" references.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2022-02-24</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>Initial export from OLAF</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:eso-chajnantor.alma.alma_radio_receiver</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>telescope_to_instrument</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:facility:observatory.eso-chajnantor</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>telescope_to_facility</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Telescope>
    <aperture unit="m">12</aperture>
    <telescope_longitude unit="deg">292.24667</telescope_longitude>
    <telescope_latitude unit="deg">-23.01917</telescope_latitude>
    <telescope_altitude unit="m">5059</telescope_altitude>
    <coordinate_source>Unknown</coordinate_source>
    <description>The Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array, or ALMA, is an international
collaboration to operate a telescope of revolutionary design from a site in the
foothills of Chile's Andes Mountains. ALMA is composed of 66 high precision antennae,
operating at wavelengths of 0.32 to 3.6 mm. Its main 12-meter array has fifty
antennae, each measuring 12 meters in diameter, acting together as a single telescope
— an interferometer. An additional compact array of four 12-meter and twelve 7-meter
antennas complements this. The ALMA antennae can be arranged in different
configurations, where the maximum distance between antennae can vary from 150 meters
to 16 kilometers. The ALMA correlator, a specialized computer that combines the
information received by the antennae, can perform a remarkable 16000 million-million
(1.6x1016) operations per second.

ALMA was inaugurated in 2013, but early scientific observations using a partial array
already began in 2011.

ALMA is a partnership between ESO (representing its Member States), NSF (USA) and
NINS (Japan), together with NRC (Canada), NSC and ASIAA (Taiwan), and KASI (South
Korea), in cooperation with the Republic of Chile. The Joint ALMA Observatory is
operated by ESO, AUI/NRAO and NAOJ.

Each radio receiver type is sensitive to a particular wavelength range (band), and
data can only be taken in one band at a time.

To date, eight out of a planned ten receivers have been installed on each ALMA
antenna. These bands range from band 3, starting at wavelengths of 3.6 mm, to band
10, ending at 0.3 mm. Band 1 is under construction (covering wavelengths between 6
and 8.5 millimeters), and band 2 (covering 3.3 to 4.5 millimeters) might be added in
the future.

Band 3: Produced by the Herzberg Institute of Astrophysics in Canada. It covers the
longest wavelength range of the bands initially installed, between 2.6-3.6 mm (84-116
GHz).
Band 4: Developed by National Astronomical Observatory of Japan (NAOJ). It covers a
wavelength range of 1.8-2.4 mm (125-163 GHz).
Band 5: Developed by the Group for Advanced Receiver Development (GARD) at Onsala
Space Observatory, Chalmers University of Technology, Sweden. The production of the
66 receivers for the ALMA observatory was done jointly by GARD and NOVA. It covers a 
wavelength range of 1.4-1.8 mm (163-211 GHz).
Band 6: Produced by the National Radio Astronomy Observatory (NRAO). It covers the
wavelength range of 1.1-1.4 mm (211-275 GHz).
Band 7: Delivered by the Institut de Radio Astronomie Millimétrique (IRAM). It covers
the wavelength range of 0.8-1.1 mm (275-373 GHz).
Band 8: Developed by NAOJ. It covers the wavelength range of 0.6-0.8 mm (385-800
GHz).
Band 9: Produced by the Nederlandse Onderzoekschool voor Astronomie (NOVA). It covers
the wavelength range 0.4-0.5 mm (602-720 GHz).
Band 10: Developed and produced led by NAOJ. It covers the wavelength range 0.3-0.4
mm (787-950 GHz).</description>
  </Telescope>
</Product_Context>
