<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.sch"
schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Context xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1M00.xsd http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/ctli/v2/PDS4_CTLI_1M00_2100.xsd">
  <Identification_Area>
    <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument:om.phx</logical_identifier>
    <version_id>1.1</version_id>
    <title>MECA OPTICAL MICROSCOPE for PHX</title>
    <information_model_version>1.22.0.0</information_model_version>
    <product_class>Product_Context</product_class>
    <Modification_History>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2018-05-23</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <description>Changed logical_identifier from om__phx to om.phx</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
      <Modification_Detail>
        <modification_date>2024-10-22</modification_date>
        <version_id>1.1</version_id>
        <description>Updated schema version. Adding missing "investigation" references. Adding missing "agency" references. Description updated.</description>
      </Modification_Detail>
    </Modification_History>
  </Identification_Area>
  <Reference_List>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:agency:agency.nasa</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_agency</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:investigation:mission.phoenix</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_investigation</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <Internal_Reference>
      <lid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context:instrument_host:spacecraft.phx</lid_reference>
      <reference_type>instrument_to_instrument_host</reference_type>
    </Internal_Reference>
    <External_Reference>
      <reference_text>
                   Keller, H.U., W. Goetz, H. Hartwig, S.F. Hviid, R. Kramm, W.J. Markiewicz, C.
                   Shinohara, P.H. Smith, R. Tanner, P. Woida, R. Woida, B.J. Bos, and M.T.
                   Lemmon, The Phoenix Robotic Arm Camera, J. Geophys. Res., 113, E00A17,
                   doi:10.1029/2007JE003044, 2008.
            </reference_text>
      <description>reference.KELLERETAL2008</description>
    </External_Reference>
  </Reference_List>
  <Instrument>
    <name>MECA OPTICAL MICROSCOPE</name>
    <type>Imager</type>
    <!--RChen/EN was Camera-->
    <naif_instrument_id>not applicable</naif_instrument_id>
    <serial_number>not applicable</serial_number>
    <description>The MECA Optical Microscope (OM) is part of the Microscopy, Electrochemistry and Conductivity Analyzer (MECA) instrument suite. The optical, electronics, and illumination systems were designed, integrated, and tested by the Lunar and Planetary Laboratory (LPL) at the University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ. It was integrated with the MECA platform, including the sample wheel and translation stage (SWTS) and Atomic Force Microscope (AFM), at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, where flight qualification was also performed. Charge Coupled Device (CCD) detector and readout electronics were delivered by the Max Planck Institute for Solar System Research (MPS), Katlenburg-Lindau, Germany. The OM is a fixed-focus imaging system utilizing a 512 x 256 pixel active imaging area frame transfer CCD detector. It is designed to acquire images of particulate Martian material (soil, dust) at a spatial resolution of 4 microns/px. The samples to be imaged are moved to the optimum focus distance (about 14 mm away from the front end of the lens barrel) via a Sample Wheel Translation Stage (SWTS). The imaged area is then 2 mm * 1 mm. The samples are actively illuminated by red, green, blue or ultraviolet Light Emitting Diodes (LEDs). Color images of these samples can be generated by combining individual images acquired with red, green and blue illumination. The SWTS is shared by the OM and the Atomic Force Microscope (AFM). It contains a total of 69 substrates: 10 sets of 6 substrates plus 9 substrates holding OM and AFM calibration targets. Each set of 6 substrates consists of a weak and a strong magnet, 2 (identical) microbuckets (empty holes, 2 mm deep, 3 mm in diameter) for bulk sampling, a nanobucket (silicon textured substrate with micron-sized pits and pillar features for fixing particles and retaining the original size distribution of the acquired sample) and a sticky silicone substrate. The SWTS can be positioned to extend any one of ten sets of 6 substrates out of the MECA enclosure to receive soil samples from the Robot Arm (RA) or to collect airfall dust. Excess material is removed by passing the substrates under a blade positioned 0.2 mm above the surface, after which the samples are rotated for imaging by the OM and AFM. The overall sensitivity of the OM extends from 400 to 1020 nm and is chiefly controlled by the sensitivity of the CCD (extending from 380 to 1020 nm) and by a Schott GG420 glass filter (placed in between CCD and lens assembly) that blocks efficiently all light in the spectral range 380-400 nm. Therefore UV LED radiation (central wavelength ~ 375 nm and spectral width ~ 12 nm) cannot be directly detected by the CCD. Illuminating the target material with ultraviolet light can thus reveal fluorescence of that material. OM images belong to a series of images (Surface Stereo Imager (SSI), Robotic Arm Camera (RAC), AFM) that inspect areas of decreasing size with increasing resolution. OM images will be used to place AFM data in context.</description>
  </Instrument>
</Product_Context>
